<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>

<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>12x70 shot rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
		<text>12x70 shot rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_descr">
		<text>Standard 12-caliber round filled with 6 mm shot. Highly lethal at close range. Only suitable for use with smoothbore weapons. Highest pierced armor class: none. Tissue damage rating: medium - high. SPECIAL: expanding cloud of pellets, short effective range</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="ammo-12.7x55-fmj">
        <text>12.7x55 mm STs-130 rounds</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-12.7x55-fmj_s">
        <text>12.7x55 mm STs-130 rounds</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-12.7x55-fmj_descr">
        <text>The 12.7x55mm subsonic cartridge is used in the VKS bullpup sniper rifle. The cartridge can carries a projectile weighing 76 grams, yielding massive amounts of kinetic energy. The round can penetrate up to 16 mm of steel at 200 meters or heavy body armor at 100 meters. The accuracy of this cartridge is claimed as to be 1 MOA at 100 meters range. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: very high</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-50-bmg">
		<text>12,7x99 mm (.50 bmg) rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-50-bmg_s">
		<text>12,7x99 mm (.50 bmg) rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-50-bmg_descr">
        <text>The .50 Browning Machine Gun (.50 BMG) or 12.7x99mm NATO is a cartridge developed for the Browning .50 caliber machine gun in the late 1910s. Entering service officially in 1921, the round is based on a greatly scaled up .30-06 cartridge. Highest pierced armor class: V. Tissue damage rating: very high</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>12x76 slug rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
		<text>12x76 slug rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_descr">
		<text>This heavy 12-caliber slug round is normally used for hunting big game, but is also good for other purposes. Instead of piercing, this hefty slug simply crushes through armor. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart">
		<text>12x76 dart rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_s">
		<text>12x76 dart rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_descr">
		<text>12-caliber dart round, normally used for hunting big game but also suitable for other purposes, including puncturing armor. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>9x18 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
		<text>9x18 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_descr">
		<text>A full metal jacket round with a steel penetrator and a lead core under a metal jacket. Provides good stopping power but is ineffective against body armor. Highest pierced armor class: II. Tissue damage rating: low - medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>Патроны 9х18 мм ПБМ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
		<text>9х18 ПБМ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_descr">
		<text>This round contains a bullet with enhanced stopping power, while its European +P+ designation indicates "overpressure ammunition" with a 30% increase in muzzle velocity. Ineffective against body armor. Highest pierced armor class: I. Tissue damage rating: medium - high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>9x19 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
		<text>9x19 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_descr">
		<text>This basic 9x19 caliber round with a jacketed bullet has good characteristics while being simple to produce. The round is popular due to the fact that international conventions prohibit the use of expanding ammunition in combat. Ineffective against body armor. Highest pierced armor class: I. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>9x19 mm JHP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
		<text>9x19 mm JHP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_descr">
		<text>This 9x19 caliber jacketed hollow-point bullet with an expanding hollow has high stopping power and low ricochet propensity. Used by police and for self-defense. Ineffective against body armor due to its low penetration potential. Highest pierced armor class: I. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->	
	<string id="ammo-5.7x28-fmj">
		<text>5,7x28 mm SS190 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.7x28-fmj_s">
		<text>5,7x28 mm SS190 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.7x28-fmj_descr">
		<text>The FN 5.7x28mm is a high velocity cartridge designed and manufactured by FN Herstal. It is a bottlenecked centerfire cartridge that is somewhat similar to the .22 Hornet or .22 K-Hornet. The 5.7x28mm was developed in conjunction with the FN P90 personal defense weapon (PDW) and FN Five-seven pistol, in response to NATO requests for a replacement for the 9x19mm Parabellum cartridge. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: low - medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-5.7x28-ap">
		<text>5,7x28 mm SS195 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.7x28-ap_s">
		<text>5,7x28 mm SS195 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.7x28-ap_descr">
		<text>5,7x28 SS195 JHP - патрон с экспансивной пулей, обладает меньшей пробивной способностью, чем SS190, но большим останавливающим действием и убойной силой.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-50-ae">
        <text>.50 Action Express rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-50-ae_s">
        <text>.50 Action Express rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-50-ae_descr">
        <text>.50 Action Express (12.7x33 mm) is a cartridge developed in 1988 for the Israeli Desert Eagle pistol. One of the most powerful pistol cartridges in the world, the .50 AE features a blunt bullet that leads to immense stopping power and the ability to snap your wrist. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-357">
        <text>.357 Magnum rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-357_s">
        <text>.357 Magnum rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-357_descr">
        <text>This round was created in 1935 as a joint effort between Smith &amp; Wesson and Remington to produce a more powerful revolver round for American law enforcement. Despite its age, it is still an extremely popular revolver round. Highest pierced armor class: II. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>.45 ACP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
		<text>.45 ACP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_descr">
		<text>The .45 caliber full metal jacket round has enjoyed popularity for a hundred years thanks to its ballistic performance and a relatively small propelling charge. As a result, the bullet in this round is relatively slow but highly accurate and provides considerable stopping power. Highest pierced armor class: II. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>.45 Hydra-shock rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
		<text>.45 Hydra-shock rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_descr">
		<text>This unusual .45 ACP caliber round is comprised of a jacketed soft point bullet with a hollow steel core, possessing both their advantages and disadvantages. Highest pierced armor class: II. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>5.45x39 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
		<text>5.45x39 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_descr">
		<text>Military 5.45x39 7H10 caliber is an improved piercing round for automatic rifles of Warsaw Pact countries. Provides better accuracy than the 7.62 caliber round thanks to reduced recoil and a 100 meter increase in range. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_descr">
		<text>Military 5.45x39 7H22 caliber armor-piercing round for automatic rifles of Warsaw Pact countries. The bullet contains a hard-alloy armor piercing penetrator. Effective against body armor. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>5.56x45 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
		<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
		<text>5.56x45 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_descr">
		<text>A standard-issue NATO 5.56x45 caliber round specially designed for accurate automatic fire. Provides good ballistic characteristics, having been designed on the basis of a hunting round. Widely known under its SS109 index. Highest pierced armor class: II. Tissue damage rating: high. SPECIAL: lowered piercing capability, enhanced fragmentation in soft tissue</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_descr">
		<text>A common NATO military 5.56x45 caliber armor piercing round, known under its SS190/M855 index, widely used by Western security agencies and special forces. Effective against body armor. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-5 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_s">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-5 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_descr">
		<text>The SP-5 is a subsonic rifle round with a bimetallic casing. The round contains a steel core with a gap behind it that is filled with lead. Requires a suppressor for stealth firing. Used by special services of Warsaw Pact countries. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: medium - high. SPECIAL: sub-sonic ammunition greatly increased projectile drop with distance</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-5 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-5 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_descr">
		<text>The SP-5 is a subsonic rifle round with a bimetallic casing. The round contains a steel core with a gap behind it that is filled with lead. Requires a suppressor for stealth firing. Used by special services of Warsaw Pact countries. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: medium - high. SPECIAL: sub-sonic ammunition greatly increased projectile drop with distance</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-ap_descr">
		<text>The SP-6 is a subsonic armor-piercing round with a jacketed soft point bullet with a hard steel core that protrudes from the casing. Requires a suppressor for stealth firing. Used by special services of Warsaw Pact countries. Effective against body armor. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: medium - high. SPECIAL: sub-sonic ammunition greatly increased projectile drop with distance</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p">
		<text>7.62x25 mm P rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p_s">
		<text>7.62x25 mm P rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p_descr">
		<text>The 7.62x25mm cartridge is a Russian bottle-necked pistol cartridge widely used in former Soviet satellite states, China and Pakistan among other countries. The cartridge is an enhanced Russian version of the 7.63x25mm Mauser. It has an excellent penetration and can easily defeat lighter ballistic vests as well as kevlar helmets. Although most firearms chambered in this caliber are obsolete and removed from military inventories, the cartridge still sees widespread use because of the large quantity of stored ammunition available. Highest pierced armor class: I. Tissue damage rating: low - medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps">
		<text>7,62x25 mm PS rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps_s">
		<text>7,62x25 mm PS rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps_descr">
		<text>The steel core 7.62x25mm cartridge is a Russian bottle-necked pistol cartridge widely used in former Soviet satellite states, China and Pakistan among other countries. It's very effective against unarmored targets. Highest pierced armor class: II. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39_fmj">
		<text>7.62x39 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39_fmj_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39_fmj_descr">
		<text>7.62x39 Full Metal Jacket is one the most commonly used types of ammunition, especially in Africa and in the Middle East. Some nicknamed it the "Round of the Revolution" due to its favored use by both terrorist and criminal organizations. Due to the sheer power of the round most military organizations have turned to using additional steel plates to counter 7.62x39 as there is a high probability of encountering it in combat situations. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap">
		<text>7.62x39 mm M43 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm M43 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap_descr">
		<text>7.62x39 M43 is an armor piercing round produced in China, which is why it's often referred to as "7.62x39 CN". This round features a mild steel core which enhances its penetration capabilities. This Chinese round (as well as all other M43 ammunition) is currently banned for import in the US because US federal law classifies the round as an armor-piercing handgun round. This classification is based on materials and bullet design rather than on empirical ability to penetrate armor. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x51-fmj">
		<text>7.62x51 mm NATO rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x51-fmj_s">
		<text>7.62x51 mm NATO rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x51-fmj_descr">
		<text>The 7.62x51 NATO round is a military variant of the .308 round which was used as a standard-issue by the NATO forces until 5.56 ammunition was introduced in the '70s in the Vietnam War. At present, it is most commonly employed by private military contractors all over the world. The 7.62x51 round is a very common machine gun caliber, and can also be used in sniper rifles. Highest pierced armor class: III. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x51-ap">
		<text>7.62x51 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x51-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x51 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x51_ap_descr">
		<text>7.62x51 NATO armor-piercing rounds with a tungsten core. Pierces any known body armor in The Zone. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
		<text>7.62x54 mm 7N1 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_s">
		<text>7.62x54 mm 7N1 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_descr">
		<text>A 7.62 caliber sniper round with a steel penetrator specially designed for the SVD. Unlike the machine gun round, the 7N1 provides tight groupings and excellent penetration characteristics. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
        <text>7.62x54 mm 7N14 rounds</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
        <text>7.62x54 mm 7N14 rounds</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_descr">
		<text>The 7.62x54mm N14 is an armor-piercing cartridge. The bullet has a steel core to penetrate body armor or light barriers, and a boat-tail base to increase accuracy. Highest pierced armor class: V. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
        <text>7.62x54 mm PP rounds</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
        <text>7.62x54 mm PP rounds</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_descr">
		<text>Cheap 7.62 caliber machine gun round. Its design makes it unsuitable for sniper rifles, so it is used only with the PKM machine gun. It is a high-powered round and thanks to a hard steel core it possesses quite good penetrative capabilities. A heavy round for a heavy gun. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-8,6x70-fmj">
		<text>.338 Lapua Magnum rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-8,6x70-fmj_s">
		<text>.338 Lapua Magnum rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-8,6x70-fmj_descr">
		<text>The .338 Lapua Magnum is a specialized rimless bottlenecked center-fire cartridge developed for military long-range sniper rifles. The Afghanistan War and Iraq War made it a combat-proven round with ready and substantial ammunition availability. The .338 Lapua is a dual-purpose anti-personnel and anti-materiel round, but its anti-materiel potential is limited. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
  <string id="ammo-gauss">
		<text>Batteries</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss_descr">
		<text>Batteries that use a encapsulated fragment of the Flash artefact as their power source. Manufactured using hi-tech equipment.</text>
  </string>
<!-- insert name -->
  <string id="ammo-gauss_cardan">
		<text>Homemade batteries</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss_cardan_descr">
		<text>These lower-capacity cells use encapsulated fragments of the Flash artefact as their power source. Their lower capacity is due to makeshift production conditions and lack of specialized equipment.</text>
  </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-pkm">
		<text>7.62x54 mm PP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-pkm_s">
		<text>7.62x54 mm PP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-pkm_descr">
		<text>Cheap 7.62 caliber machine gun round. Its design makes it unsuitable for sniper rifles, so it is used only with the PKM machine gun. It is a high-powered round and thanks to a hard steel core it possesses quite good penetrative capabilities. A heavy round for a heavy gun. Highest pierced armor class: IV. Tissue damage rating: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="ammo-og-7b">
        <text>OG-7V warhead</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
        <text>OG-7V</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-og-7b_descr">
        <text>Fragmentation warhead for anti-personnel warfare used with the RPG-7u grenade launcher. The main purpose of the warhead is to kill enemies in cover outside the range of hand grenades using the RPG-7u launcher.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_grenade_f1">
        <text>F1 grenade</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_grenade_f1_descr">
        <text>A defensive hand grenade, with fragments capable of piercing medium level body armor. The grenade has a 7 meter kill radius. Stalkers get F1 grenades from trading with the military, who write them off as having been used for fighting mutants.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_grenade_rgd5">
        <text>RGD-5 grenade</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_grenade_rgd5_descr">
        <text>An offensive hand grenade with a small kill zone of 5 meters. Often used by stalkers to "smoke out" mutants due to its relatively low cost.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_grenade_smoke">
        <text>Smoke grenade</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_grenade_smoke_descr">
        <text>A hand smoke grenade. Used to put up smoke screens. Once the grenade is thrown it takes 10 seconds for the smoke screen to expand.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_grenade_light_descr">
		<text>Химическая осветительная граната. Предназначена для освещения участков местности во время ночного боя, а также для ослепления и дезориентации противника. Время действия меньше минуты.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_light">
		<text>Граната GL-1</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="ammo-vog-25">
        <text>VOG-25 grenade</text>
    </string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
        <text>VOG-25</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-vog-25_descr">
        <text>Regular fragmentation grenade for the GP-25 Koster underbarrel grenade launcher. This round has a 5 meter kill zone. The VOG-25 grenade is also used in the Thunder S14 complex and Bulldog 6 revolver-type grenade launcher.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="ammo-vog-25p">
		<text>Выстрел ВОГ-25П</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25p_s">
		<text>ВОГ-25П</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25p_descr">
		<text>40мм выстрел ВОГ-25П или «Подкидыш» (7П24) - осколочная граната для гранатометов, у которой главное и основное отличие заключается в головном взрывателе, обеспечивающим «подпрыгивание» гранаты после удара о грунт и её разрыв в воздухе, что увеличивает её поражающее действие.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="ammo-m209">
        <text>M203 grenade</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-m209_s">
        <text>M203 grenade</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-m209_descr">
        <text>40 mm grenade for the M203 underbarrel grenade launcher. This round has a 5 meter kill zone. Also suitable for use in the FT-200M integrated grenade launcher.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_galil">
		<text>Galil 4.0x scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_galil_descr">
		<text>Optical sight for the Israeli IMI Galil rifle. Magnification: 4.0x, reticule pattern: SUSAT</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_4x34">
        <text>PO 4x34 scope</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_4x34_descr">
        <text>Optical sight featuring variable magnification. Used on hunting rifles and are designed for precise focus when shooting. The sights are mounted using special brackets.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_1p29">
        <text>1P29 "Tulip" Scope</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_1p29_descr">
        <text>The USP-1 sight (index 1P29) has an optical arrangement with a prism-erecting system. Sighting angles are set mechanically by turning the sight body relative to the weapon mounting bracket. Requires no batteries as it is tritium illuminated. The ranging scale at the edge of the sight's field of view provides a means to find visually the range of up to 1200 m of a target 1.5 m high.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_1pn93">
		<text>1PN93-4 "Tot" Scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_1pn93_descr">
        <text>Russian night sight designed to monitor the battlefield and assist aimed shooting in bad visibility.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_kobra-ekp-1s-03">
        <text>Kobra</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_kobra_descr">
        <text>The Kobra sight is an open collimator combat optic using a laser generated HUD to superimpose a reticle pattern onto a filtered lens. It is designed for engaging fast moving targets and targets appearing for a short period of time in close quarters and urban combat in various light conditions. It provides clear targeting from 104 lx to 10-2 lx (daylight, twilight and moonlight), one or two eye targeting. Effective when shooting from moving vehicles.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon-ekp-8-02">
        <text>EKP-8-02</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon-ekp-8-02_descr">
        <text>The EKP-8-02 is an open collimator red dot combat optic using a laser generated HUD to superimpose a reticle pattern onto a filtered lens. It is designed for engaging fast moving targets and targets appearing for a short period of time in close quarters and urban combat situations in various light conditions. It provides clear targeting from 104 lx to 10-2 lx (daylight, twilight and moonlight), one- or two-eye targeting, is very effective when shooting from moving vehicles, and allows for perfect kill shots on fast-moving, small and spontaneously appearing targets.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_eotech">
        <text>EO-Tech Sight</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_eotech_descr">
        <text>Holographic sight for NATO assault rifles and sub-machine guns</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_c-more">
        <text>C-MORE Tactical Sight</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_c-more_descr">
        <text>High performance red dot sight that provides an unlimited field of view, while eliminating obstruction and tunnel vision common to tube style scopes.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_docter_sight">
        <text>DOCTER Sight</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_docter_sight_descr">
        <text>Due to its light weight as well as compact pipeless design, these sights see wide spread use in hunting and for sport. Reliable performance, high optical power, attractive design and trouble-free operation even in extreme weather conditions makes DOCTER sight irreplaceable.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_pk-a">
        <text>PK-A scope</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_pk-a_descr">
        <text>The PK-A red dot sight is a reflex sight produced by BelOMO in Minsk, Belarus. The sight is compatible with side-mounted systems commonly found on AK, SKS, and SVD-type rifles. The sight uses a single red dot within a nitrogen-filled lens setup and has eight brightness levels.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->	
    <string id="st_addon_scope_acog">
        <text>Trijicon ACOG</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_acog_descr">
        <text>Advanced Combat Optical Gunsights are a series of telescopic sights manufactured by Trijicon. Can be mounted on NATO assault rifles and sub-machine guns as well as the AK-12.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_ac10632">
        <text>Barska ELECTRO SIGHT AC10632</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_ac10632_descr">
        <text>The Barska Electro Sight Multi Reticle Red Dot Sight AC10632 was developed in order to be the best product for anybody looking for a high quality sights.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_ac11090">
        <text>AC11090 Red Dot Sight</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_ac11090_descr">
        <text>Cheap 2x magnification red dot sight for NATO assault rifles and sub-machine guns.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope">
		<text>PSO-1M scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_descr">
		<text>PSO (for Pritsel Snaipersky Optichesky, "Optical Sniper Sight") is a series of Soviet-made optical scopes produced by Novosibirsk Instrument-Making Plant (NPZ Optics State Plant). In common use since 1964 when it was introduced as a standard issue telescopic sight for SVD sniper rifle. The scope has been later adapted to assault rifles such as AK-74 or AN-94. Recognized for its durability, versatility and very well-designed reticule pattern featuring convenient range-finder scale. This particular type has 4.0x magnification rate, making it usable mainly for combat at long ranges. It is attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount, which is standard in Warsaw Pact countries. Magnification: 4.0x, reticule pattern: PSO-1</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_pso-1m2-01">
		<text> PSO-1M2-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_pso-1m2-01_descr">
		<text>The PSO-1M2-O1 features an extremely effective and useful height-based rangefinder for dual use, with graduated scales for both standing and prone figure estimation. The 400 meter Simonov height based gradient (choke style) rangefinder has a chevron for use with the 9x39 caliber rifles. Magnification: 4.0x, reticule pattern: PSO-1-1</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7">
        <text>PSU-1 scope</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7_descr">
        <text>A 2.7x optical scope for urban combat at medium range. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision">
        <text>NSPU-3 scope</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision_descr">
        <text>An image intensifier night vision 5.0x fixed zoom scope for combat in darkness. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat">
        <text>SUSAT 4x scope</text>
    </string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_descr">
        <text>A 4x fixed zoom scope produced primarily in Western countries. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail. Often used for accurate fire from small arms at medium to long range.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6">
        <text>SUSAT 1.6x scope</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6_descr">
        <text>An optical SUSAT 1.6x scope for combat at short to medium range. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk">
        <text>SUSAT Twilight x1.6 scope</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk_descr">
        <text>An optical SUSAT 1.6x higher contrast scope for combat in reduced lighting conditions. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision">
        <text>SUSAT Night x4 scope</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision_descr">
        <text>A 4.0x fixed zoom scope with a night vision device for long range combat in darkness. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom">
        <text>SUSAT Mera scope</text>
    </string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom_descr">
        <text>An adjustable long-range 1.6-4x zoom scope that can use automatic adjustment to provide greater fire effectiveness. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_silencer">
		<text>9mm suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_silencer_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for 9mm pistols and submachine guns. An effective sound suppressor for caliber 9x18 weapons. It is very archaic and yet quite effective. Its body contains a tightly-packed roll of fine brass mesh. The front of the unit comprises a set of rubber wipes with caliber-sized holes for the bullet to pass through. Normally used for close-combat engagements against lightly-armored enemies and for assassinations. Sound suppression: very high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_6p9">
		<text>6P9 suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_6p9_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for the PB pistol. Sound suppression: very high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_57">
		<text>5.7x28 suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_57_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for the FN-P90 PDW. Sound suppression: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_9a91">
		<text>9A-91/VSK-94 suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_9a91_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for the 9A-91 carbine and VSK-94. Sound suppression: very high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_gemtech">
		<text>Gemtech suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_gemtech_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for the Glock and the FN-FNP. Sound suppression: high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_vihr">
		<text>SR-3M suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_vihr_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for the SR-3M rifle. Sound suppression: very high</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_45">
		<text>.45 ACP suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_45_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for .45 ACP pistols and submachine guns. Sound suppression: very high (pistol)</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_atg">
		<text>ATG suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_atg_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for the AK-102, AK-103 and AK-104. Sound suppression: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_tgp-a">
		<text>TGP-A suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_tgp-a_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for AK rifle series and RPK-74 machine guns. Sound suppression: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_pbs-1">
		<text>PBS-1 suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_pbs-1_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for noiseless and flameless firing from Kalashnikov 7.62mm. Sound suppression: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_pbs4">
		<text>PBS-4 suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_pbs4_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for AKS-74U rifle. Sound suppression: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_kzrzp">
		<text>KZRZP suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_kzrzp_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for the SVD sniper rifle. Sound suppression: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_nato">
		<text>NATO Suppressor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_nato_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for 5.56x45 assault rifles. It consists of hi-grade steel body filled with four extension chambers, followed by a series of Z-type titanium baffles. The unit almost completely reduces muzzle flash and considerably suppresses sound emitted when firing. It also requires minimum maintenance. Suppressors of this and similar types are commonly used on all smallbore Western-made rifles and remain in active service in Western armed forces.Sound suppression: medium</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_sil_sr25">
		<text>G&amp;P SR-25 Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_sil_sr25_descr">
		<text>Suppressor for the SR-25</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher">
		<text>GP-25 "Kostyor" grenade launcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_descr">
		<text>A single shot, front loaded, rifled underbarrel grenade launcher for assault rifles made in Warsaw Pact countries. Designed to greatly expand fire-power of a basic infantry squad. The firing mechanism is self-cocking, with a manual safety catch and automatic shot prevention if incorrectly installed onto a rifle.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203">
		<text>M203 grenade launcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203_descr">
		<text>A modified M203 grenade launcher whose length has been decreased by three inches, and which can be attached to weapons by means of a Picatinny rail. Thanks to a changed mount, this grenade launcher is widely used around the world and can be installed on most currently produced rifles. Although of more modern design, it has almost the same properties as its Soviet counterpart - the GP-25 grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_grenade_launcher_ag36">
        <text>H&amp;K AG36</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_grenade_launcher_ag36_descr">
        <text>The AG36 is a single-shot 40 mm grenade launcher that operates on the High-Low System and was designed primarily for installation on the G36 assault rifle, designed by the German weapons manufacturing company Heckler&amp;Koch.</text>
    </string>
<!-- 9A-91 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_9a91">
        <text>9A-91</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_9a91_descr">
        <text>The 9A-91 is a carbine assault rifle currently in use with Russian police forces. It is a gas operated, rotating bolt weapon, which utilizes a long stroke gas piston, located above the barrel, and a rotating bolt with 4 lugs. The receiver is made from steel stampings; the fore-end and pistol grip are made from polymer. The steel butt-stock folds up and above the receiver when not in use. The charging handle is welded to the right side of bolt carrier. The safety / fire selector lever is located at the left side of the receiver, above the trigger guard, and allows for semi- and full-automatic fire. The flip-up rear sight has settings for 100 and 200 meters range, but the relatively short sight base and steep trajectory of the subsonic bullet effectively restricts the 9A91 to ranges of about 100 meters.</text>
    </string>
<!-- АН-94 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan">
		<text>АN-94</text>
	</string>
  <string id="st_wpn_abakan_descr">
		<text>A modern assault rifle developed as a replacement for the aging AKM 74/2. The main difference is its high speed 2-round burst firing mode, which allows two bullets to be fired at exactly the same spot on a target up to 100 meters away. This significantly increases the likelihood of hitting the target in comparison to the 1 round firing mode, which considerably improves kill potential, stopping power and armor piercing capability.</text>
  </string>
<!-- АЕК-971 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_aek971">
        <text>AEK-971</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_aek971_descr">
        <text>The AEK-971 5.45x39 assault rifle based on previous AK rifles in internal design and layout, but is also equipped with a recoil-balancing mechanism by way of a counter-weight that negates the impulse of the gas piston and bolt carrier, resulting in more controllable automatic fire.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_ak12">
        <text>AK-12</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_ak12_descr">
        <text>The AK12 is the next generation model of the 5.45x39 AK series. The rifle comes standard with picatinny rails, an adjustable telescoping stock and the rear sight has been moved to the back of the receiver. The rifle has a new muzzle brake and improved rifling, making it more accurate than the other AK assault rifles. It has gained popularity in the Duty faction.</text>
    </string>
<!-- АК -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ak">
		<text>АК-47</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak_descr">
        <text>The AK-47 can be described as a hybrid of previous rifle technology.It is a selective-fire, gas-operated 7.62x39 assault rifle combining the best features of the American M1 and the German StG44, first developed in the Soviet Union by Mikhail Kalashnikov. By far the most prolific small arm of the 2nd half of the 20th century. It had been and still is, in more or less modified form, manufactured in dozens of countries and has been used in hundreds of conflicts since its introduction.</text>
	</string>
<!-- АКС -->
	<string id="st_wpn_aks">
		<text>AKS-47</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_aks_descr">
        <text>The main variant of the AK-47 was the AKS-47, which was equipped with an under folding metal shoulder stock in place of the fixed wooden stock. It was designed for use inside armored vehicles and by paratroopers.</text>
	</string>
<!-- АК-74 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74">
		<text>АК-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_descr">
		<text>This weapon, designed in 1974, signaled the adoption of small calibre and low impulse rounds by Warsaw Pact countries. A descendant of the most popular assault rifle in the world, the AK-74 has a bigger muzzle brake, resulting in a reduction of what was already manageable recoil. This facilitates better accuracy and groupings, especially when fired in fast single shots or bursts. As before, the rifle is very simple and reliable.</text>
	</string>
<!-- АК-74М -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m">
		<text>АК-74М</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74m_camo">
		<text>АК-74М (камуфляж)</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_wpn_ak74m_descr">
        <text>The AK-74M is a modernized version of the AK-74 assault rifle. It features a new synthetic stock made from a black, glass-filled polyamide that also side-folds like in the AKS-74. Additionally the AK-74M features an improved muzzle device, a reinforced smooth dust cover and a redesigned guide rod return spring retainer that allows firing the GP-25 under-slung grenade launcher without having to use the previously necessary additional receiver cover fastener.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_ak101">
        <text>AK-101</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_ak101_descr">
        <text>The AK-101 is an assault rifle of the Kalashnikov series designed for the world export market, using 5.56x45mm NATO cartridges, which is the standard of most NATO armies. The AK-101 is marketed at those looking for a weapon that combines the logistical compatibility and familiarity of the 5.56x45mm NATO round with the reliability of a Kalashnikov. It is designed with modern and composite materials, including plastics that reduce weight and improve accuracy. Many of the improvements found in the AK-101 are also present in the AK-103 and the rest of the AK-10x series of rifles.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_ak102">
        <text>AK-102</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_ak102_descr">
        <text>The AK-102 is a 5.56x45 shortened carbine version of the AK-101 rifle. It features a shortened barrel that makes it a middle ground between a full rifle and the more compact AKS-74U. The rifle's receiver is made of stamped steel. The magazine is made out of reinforced fiberglass. The butt stock is made of hollow plastic, making it lighter, more durable, and allowing a field kit to be stored in side of it.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_ak103">
        <text>AK-103</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_ak103_descr">
        <text>The AK-103 assault rifle is a derivative of the AK-74M chambered for 7.62x39, same as the AKM and AK-47. The AK-103 can be fitted with a variety of sights, including laser, night vision, and telescopic sights, plus a suppressor and the GP-25 grenade launcher. It uses plastic components whenever possible instead of wood or metal in order to reduce weight.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_ak104">
        <text>AK-104</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_ak104_descr">
        <text>The AK-104 is a 7.62x39 shortened carbine version of the AK-103 rifle. It features a shortened barrel that makes it a middle ground between a full rifle and the more compact AKS-74U. The rifle's receiver is made of stamped steel. The magazine is made out of reinforced fiberglass. The butt stock is made of hollow plastic, making it lighter, more durable, and allowing a field kit to be stored in side of it.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_ak105">
        <text>AK-105</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_ak105_descr">
        <text>The AK-105 is a 5.45x39 shortened carbine version of the AK-74M rifle. It features a shortened barrel that makes it a middle ground between a full rifle and the more compact AKS-74U. The rifle's receiver is made of stamped steel. The magazine is made out of reinforced fiberglass. The butt stock is made of hollow plastic, making it lighter, more durable, and allowing a field kit to be stored in side of it.</text>
    </string>
<!-- АКМ -->
	<string id="st_wpn_akm">
		<text>АКМ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_akm_raider">
		<text>АКМ (потрёпанный)</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_wpn_akm_descr">
        <text>The AKM is an upgraded version of the AK-47 rifle and is the most common variant of the entire AK series of firearms. It has found widespread use with most member states of the former Warsaw Pact. A favorite weapon among experienced Stalkers due to its power and reliability.</text>
    </string>
<!-- АКМС -->
    <string id="st_wpn_akms">
        <text>AKMS</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_akms_descr">
        <text>The main variant of the AKM is the AKMS, which was equipped with an under folding metal shoulder stock in place of the fixed wooden stock. A favorite weapon among experienced Stalkers due to its power, reliability and more compact size.</text>
    </string>
<!-- АКС-74 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_aks74">
        <text>AKS-74</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_aks74_descr">
        <text>A variant of the AK-74 equipped with a side-folding metal shoulder stock, designed primarily for use with air assault infantry. Does nothing fancy, but weighs 100 grams less than the AK-74.</text>
    </string>
<!-- АКС-74У -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u">
		<text>AKS-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_descr">
		<text>Despite being similar to submachine guns in size, weight and tactical purpose, this weapon is classified as an assault rifle due to its use of the same intermediate cartridge as its larger cousin the AK-74. The weapon is notable for its mobility in close quarters and high armor-penetration capacity, while its drawbacks are its short effective range, despite the relatively long bullet range, a tendency to overheat and high ricochet propensity.</text>
	</string>
<!-- АКС-74У -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag">
		<text>AKS-74U Kobra</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag_descr">
		<text>A special version of the AKS-74U sub-assault rifle, equipped with Cobra sight and PBS-4 silencer.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Steyr AUG A1 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_aug">
        <text>Steyr AUG A1</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_aug_descr">
        <text>The Steyr AUG is an Austrian bullpup 5.56x45mm assault rifle, designed in the 1960s by Steyr Mannlicher. It was adopted by the Austrian Army in 1978 and is the standard rifle of the Bundesheer and various national police units.</text>
    </string>
<!-- L96A1 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_l96a1">
		<text>L96A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_l96a1_descr">
        <text>The L96A1 is a bolt action sniper rifle chambered in 7.62x51 NATO. In 1982 the British Army adopted the Accuracy International PM into service as the L96A1 and outfitted the rifle with Schmidt &amp; Bender 6x42 telescopic sights. In this configuration the rifle is capable of first shot hits with a cold, warm or fouled barrel.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Barrett M98B -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m98b">
		<text>Barrett M98B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m98b_descr">
		<text>The Barrett M98B is a bolt-action sniper rifle chambered in .338 Lapua Mag. Rather than modifying a hunting rifle, Barrett created an original design for the M98B. The M98B features an adjustable stock and cheek pad for comfort, an adjustable trigger for preferable trigger control, a rear monopod and a front bi-pod for stability. Users can further modify the rifle by attaching sights, lights and grips to its rails. The M98B has a simple design making it easy for users to disassemble and clean.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Cz-52 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_cz52">
        <text>CZ 52</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_cz52_descr">
        <text>The CZ 52 is a surplus 7.62x25 pistol designed in the early 1950s for the Czechoslovakian military. The lighter bullet and longer casing give this pistol a higher muzzle velocity then most pistols. Technicians are not interested in upgrading surplus weapons.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Cz-75 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_cz75">
        <text>CZ 75</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_cz75_descr">
        <text>The CZ 75 is a pistol made by CZUB in the Czech Republic. First introduced in 1975, it is one of the original "wonder nines" featuring a staggered-column magazine, all-steel construction, and a hammer forged barrel. It has a good reputation for quality and versatility.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K G3 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_g3">
        <text>H&amp;K G3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_g3_descr">
        <text>The Grandfather G3 battle rifle developed in the 1950s by the German armament manufacturer Heckler&amp;Koch. Well known for its accuracy and high degree of craftsmanship. The G3 series is without argument one of the best and most popular 7.62x51mm NATO caliber combat rifles in history, used by over 50 countries since its creation.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K G3A3 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_g3a3">
        <text>H&amp;K G3A3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_g3a3_descr">
        <text>The H&amp;K G3A3 is a 7.62 NATO battle rifle developed in the 1950s by the German armament manufacturer Heckler&amp;Koch. Well known for its accuracy and high degree of craftsmanship. The G3 series is without argument one of the best and most popular 7.62x51mm NATO caliber combat rifles in history, used by over 50 countries since its creation.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K G3SG1 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_g3sg1">
        <text>H&amp;K G3SG/1</text>
    </string>
	<string id="st_wpn_g3sg1_descr">
		<text>A sniper variant of the G3. The "SG" stands for Scharfschutzengewehr, or "sharpshooting rifle". The rifles were individually selected from the production line for their accuracy and then modified. A Zeiss 1.5-6x variable power telescopic sight was added using a H&amp;K claw mount attached to the receiver. The stock was extended slightly and comes with a heavy, dual-stage buffer and adjustable cheek rest. A special set trigger group was added for a crisp trigger pull of 1 lb. Automatic fire was retained.</text>
	</string>
<!-- FN Five-seveN -->
	<string id="st_wpn_fn57">
		<text>FN Five-seveN</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fn57_descr">
		<text>The Five-seveN is a delayed blowback operated, semi automatic firearm. The Five-seveN pistol was designed by FN Herstal as a complimentary sidearm for the P90 submachine gun. The P90 and Five-seveN share the same ammunition, the 5.7x28mm SS190 cartridge. The idea behind the ammunition and weapon is to provide good penetration against targets protected by body armor, while keeping the weapon's weight, dimensions and recoil at reasonable levels.</text>
	</string>
<!-- FN FNP -->
	<string id="st_wpn_fnp45">
		<text>FNP-45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fnp45_descr">
		<text>The FN FNP pistol is a series of semi automatic, polymer framed pistols manufactured in Columbia, South Carolina by FNH USA, a division of Fabrique Nationale de Herstal. Debuted in early 2006, the FNP series weapons are hammer fired weapons utilizing a Browning cam system with an external extractor. The trigger module is housed inside the polymer frame as an individual unit connected to the hammer. The magazine release button is held in place by a retention pin which can be removed to allow the button to be reversed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fnx45">
		<text>FNX-45 "Tactical"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fnx45_descr">
		<text>The FNX line of pistols were introduced in 2009 by FNH USA, a US based subsidiary of the Belgian gun company FN Herstal. Originally developed to the requirements of the US Joint Combat Pistol Program, these pistols are manufactured in US and intended for military, law enforcement and civilian use. All FNX handguns are semi automatic pistols with double/single action trigger and external hammer. Frame of the every FNX pistol is made from impact resistant polymer, with removable backstraps of different sizes. FNX-45 Tactical is a specialized variant of the basic FNX-45, that features extended threaded barrel and raised sights, to be used with detachable sound suppressor.</text>
	</string>
<!-- МП-443 «Грач» -->
    <string id="st_wpn_mp443">
        <text>MP-443 Grach</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_mp443_descr">
        <text>The MP-443 Grach is a Russian semi-automatic pistol designed by Vladimir Yarygin in the 1990s and manufactured by Izhevsk Mechanical Plant. It was developed in response to Russian military trials, which began in 1993, to replace the Makarov PMM. The pistol was designed to be capable of firing over-pressurized versions of the 9x19mm Parabellum round (7N21) which are more  capable of piercing armor.</text>
    </string>
<!-- ТТ-33 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_tt33">
		<text>ТТ-33</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_wpn_tt33_descr">
        <text>The TT-33 is a Russian 7.62x25 pistol. It was developed in the early 1930s by Fedor Tokarev as a service pistol for the Soviet military to replace the Nagant M1895 revolver.</text>
    </string>
<!-- ОЦ-33 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_oc33">
		<text>OTs-33 "Pernach"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_oc33_descr">
		<text>OTs-33 "Pernach" (Russian for multivaned mace) is a recent entry into the small class of Russian automatic pistols. The OTs-33 is a blowback-operated weapon firing the 9x18mm Makarov pistol cartridge in automatic and semi-automatic mode. The Pernach was developed in 1995 to replace the Stechkin APS pistol in special paramilitary units. Designed in 1995 by Igor Stechkin at the TSKIB SOO, Central Design Bureau for Sporting and Hunting arms, Tula, Russia, the same designer who developed the APS.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ГШ-18 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_gsh18">
        <text>GSh-18</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_gsh18_descr">
        <text>The GSh-18 is a 9 mm semi-automatic pistol developed in 1990s at the KBP Instrument Design Bureau in Tula. The pistol's name is derived from its designers — Gryazev and Shipunov, and the number 18 denotes the magazine capacity.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Glock 17 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_glock17">
        <text>Glock 17</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_glock17_descr">
        <text>Glock is a series of polymer-framed, short recoil operated, locked breech semi-automatic pistols designed and produced by Glock Ges.m.b.H., located in Deutsch-Wagram, Austria. It is widely used throughout the world in military, security and police forces. Commonly found in The Zone in 9mm, 10mm Auto, .45 ACP and .40 S&amp;W.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Glock 19-->
	<string id="st_wpn_glock19">
		<text>Glock 19</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_glock19_descr">
		<text>The Glock 19 is a smaller version of the Glock 17. Its reduced size made the Glock 19 easier to conceal and carry by military and police forces. The pistol was debuted by Glock GbmH of Austria in 1988. When compared to the Glock 17, the Glock 19 retains the weight of its slide to keep the short recoil operation in check while at the same time shortening the grip and barrel. Many components of the Glock 19 were made interchangeable with the Glock 17, including the magazine. Simply put, the Glock 19 is a compact version of the 17.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Сайга-12К -->
    <string id="st_wpn_saiga">
        <text>Saiga 12K</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_saiga_descr">
        <text>The Saiga 12 is a 12-gauge semi-automatic shotgun available in a wide range of configurations, visually patterned after the Kalashnikov series of assault rifles. Like the Kalashnikov rifle, it is a rotating bolt, gas-operated gun that feeds from an 8 round magazine.</text>
    </string>
<!-- РПК -->
    <string id="st_wpn_rpk">
        <text>RPK</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_rpk_descr">
        <text>The RPK is a 7.62x39mm light machine gun of Soviet design, developed by Mikhail Kalashnikov in the late 1950s, parallel with the AKM assault rifle. It was created as part of a program designed to standardize the small arms inventory of the Red Army, where it replaced the 7.62x39mm RPD light machine gun. The RPK continues to be used by the armed forces of countries of the former Soviet Union and certain African and Asian nations.</text>
    </string>
<!-- РПК-74 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_rpk74">
        <text>RPK-74</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_rpk74_descr">
        <text>The RPK-74 is a 5.45x39mm light machine gun of Soviet design, developed by Mikhail Kalashnikov in the late 1950s, parallel with the AKM assault rifle. It was created as part of a program designed to standardize the small arms inventory of the Red Army, where it replaced the 7.62x39mm RPD light machine gun. The RPK continues to be used by the armed forces of countries of the former Soviet Union and certain African and Asian nations.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Beretta M92 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta">
		<text>Beretta 92</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_descr">
        <text>Beretta 92f pistols enjoy the reputation of a relatively reliable, albeit somewhat cumbersome weapon, around the world. In service with armed forces and police across the ocean, as well as various military and law enforcement organizations worldwide.  The pistol is equally popular with members of the underworld, thanks to its powerful round and magazine capacity. Beretta 92f pistols found in the Zone are usually dated, probably from retired stock.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Beretta 92SB -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m9">
		<text>Beretta 92</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m9_descr">
        <text>Beretta 92f pistols enjoy the reputation of a relatively reliable, albeit somewhat cumbersome weapon, around the world. In service with armed forces and police across the ocean, as well as various military and law enforcement organizations worldwide.  The pistol is equally popular with members of the underworld, thanks to its powerful round and magazine capacity. Beretta 92f pistols found in the Zone are usually dated, probably from retired stock.</text>
	</string>
<!-- БМ-16 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_bm16">
        <text>Sawed-off TOZ-66</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_bm16_descr">
        <text>A TOZ-66 with both barrels sawn off above the hand grip, making it lighter and more compact. One of the most popular weapons among bandits due to its ease of concealment and extreme effectiveness in close combat.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Colt M1911A1 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911">
		<text>Colt M1911A1</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_wpn_colt1911_descr">
        <text>An improved version of a classic automatic pistol, which passed all the major armed conflicts of the 20th century with flying colors and entered the new millennium with confidence. Produced by dozens if not hundreds of arms manufacturers around the world in both standard and modified configurations. The weapon’s only drawback, its mediocre magazine capacity, is largely compensated by the hard-hitting ammo it uses.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Desert Eagle -->
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle">
		<text>Desert Eagle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle_descr">
        <text>The ultimate hand cannon - bulky, heavy and highly lethal. Developed as a specialized weapon for hunting medium-sized and large game, as well as for shooting competitions involving firing at steel body targets at distances over 50 meters. Its limited use in the Zone can be attributed to its price, size and weight, which are all double those of other pistols. Commonly found .50 AE and .357 Magnum and carried by experienced Bandits, Freedomers and Duty squad leaders.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle_nimble_descr">
        <text>A hand-made pistol based on the Desert Eagle design. The components are finely tuned to achieve incredible accuracy for a handgun of this type.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_famas">
		<text>FAMAS F1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_famas_descr">
		<text>FAMAS stands for Fusil d'Assaut de la Manufacture d'Armes de St-Etienne (Assault Rifle by St-Etienne Arms Factory). Development of this rifle began in 1967, by Paul Tellie, a French arms designer. This new rifle was intended to replace the aging MAS Mle.49/56 semi automatic rifles, MAT-49 submachine guns and MAC Mle.1929 light machine guns. The first FAMAS prototype had been built in 1971, and French military began to test this rifle in 1972. Meanwhile, France adopted a Swiss-designed SIG SG-540 5.56mm assault rifle as an intermediate solution. The FAMAS was adopted by the French in 1978 and since then became a standard French Army rifle, known among the French soldiers as "Le Clairon" (the bulge).</text>
	</string>
<!-- FN-2000 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000">
		<text>FN F2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_descr">
		<text>From the late 1980s to early 1990s, FN Herstal began to develop a new rifle. The aim was to produce a modern and modular weapon resulting in the FN F2000 rifle, first displayed to the public in 2001. The F2000 offers all of the popular features of the modern assault rifle such as a compact bullpup layout, ambidextrous handling and a modular design with plenty of options and addons available. So far, the FN F2000 rifle has found only a few buyers, including the Armed Forces of Slovenia and Belgian Special Operations Forces.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ПП-19 «Бизон» -->
	<string id="st_wpn_bizon">
		<text>PP-19 "Bizon"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_bizon_descr">
		<text>This submachine gun has been developed in Izhevsk at the famous IZHMASH state arms factory during the early 1990s, first appearing to the public in 1993. Influenced by the Calico submachine guns, Bizon (Bison) SMG combined high capacity helical magazine with more conventional appearance and layout. The Bizon is built on shortened AKS-74 receivers, made from stamped steel. It featured a simple blowback action, hammer fired from closed bolt. The Bizon is capable of semi automatic and automatic fire, with typical AK-type safety - selector lever at the right side of the receiver. Sights are similar to ones found on the AKS-74U, with hooded front post and flip up rear.</text>
    </string>
<!-- FN P90 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_p90">
        <text>FN P90</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_p90_descr">
        <text>The FN P90 is a personal defense weapon designed in conjunction with the FN Five-seven pistol.  Manufactured by FN Herstal in Belgium, it was created in response to NATO requests for a replacement for 9x19mm Parabellum firearms, the P90 was designed as a compact but powerful firearm for vehicle crews, operators of crew-served weapons, support personnel, special forces and counter-terrorist groups.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Форт-12 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_fort">
		<text>Fort-12</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_wpn_fort_descr">
        <text>A Ukrainian-made pistol predominantly used by law enforcement organizations. Provides higher accuracy, better ergonomics and has a larger magazine than the PMm.  These pistols make it into the Zone in large numbers thanks to the sale of defective weapons, which suffer from technical miscalculations in early design models. Despite this, the pistol is in demand among stalkers thanks to its good combat characteristics.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K G36 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_g36">
        <text>H&amp;K G36</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_g36_descr">
        <text>A new addition to the Western-made assault rifle family, which differs significantly from previous models in the series built on an automatic foundation with a semi-open bolt assembly, this weapon is more like American automatic gas-operated assault rifles with a short-stroke gas piston system. These changes ensure that the rifle is a first-rate example of a modern weapon - lightweight, reliable and ergonomic.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K G36C -->
    <string id="st_wpn_g36c">
        <text>H&amp;K G36C</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_g36c_descr">
        <text>The G36C carbine is a further development of the G36. It has a shorter barrel and a four-prong birdcage type flash hider. The extremely short barrel forced designers to move the gas block closer to the muzzle end and reduce the length of the gas piston operating rod. The dual optical sight found on the standard G36 and G36K models was replaced with a set of rail-mounted detachable iron sights that consist of a semi-shrouded front post and a flip-up rear sight.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K G36K -->
	<string id="st_wpn_g36k">
		<text>H&amp;K G36K</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_g36k_descr">
		<text>A shortened variant of the G-36 rifle with a shorter barrel, fitted with an open type flash suppressor, a shorter forend and a bottom rail that can be used to attach tactical accessories, such as a UTL flashlight. The rifle's barrel lacks the ability to launch rifle grenades and will not support a bayonet. The weapon retained the ability to use the AG36 grenade launcher. G-36K in service with German special forces are issued with a 100 round C-Mag drum. There are two variants of the G-36K, first has 3x scope with carry handle attached to the top and the second is fitted with iron sights and rail.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Гаусс -->
	<string id="st_wpn_gauss">
		<text>Gauss rifle "Item №62"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_gauss_descr">
		<text>A super-accurate hi-tech weapon known as item 62, this rifle was developed in secret laboratories located inside the Zone. The weapon operates by accelerating bullets to extremely high speeds using a system of electromagnets, which provides incredible stopping power with virtually no recoil. The weapon is powered by using capsulated artifact fragments in the batteries.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ОЦ-14 «Гроза» -->
	<string id="st_wpn_groza">
		<text>OTs-14 Groza</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_descr">
		<text>The OTs-14 "Groza" ("Thunder") modular assault rifle was developed during the early 1990s at the TSKIB SOO. It was intended for various special forces in the Russian Army and Internal Affairs Ministry as an dedicated urban warfare weapon. Briefly manufactured in small numbers at the Tula Arms factory during the mid-1990s, the OTs-14 saw action in Chechnya in 1999, but fell out of favor and are no longer being made. It is a bullpup design, with removable foregrip which can be replaced with a 40mm grenade launcher. Adopted for Spetsnaz forces and specialist front-line combat units, the OTs-14-4A allows for assembly of one of four weapon versions, depending on the mission.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Browning HP-SA -->
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa">
		<text>Browning Hi-Power</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_descr">
		<text>The Browning Hi-Power is a single-action, 9mm semi automatic pistol. It is based on the ideas of American firearms inventor John Browning, created and patented in 1922, later patented by FN Herstal. Browning died in 1926, before he had finished developing a production version, but FN arms designer Dieudonne Saive fully developed it. The Hi-Power pistol was noted for its 13 round magazine capacity, twice that of contemporary designs such as the Luger or Mauser 1910. This modified variant of the Browning HP pistol, despite its venerable age, enjoys popularity around the world.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_hk416">
        <text>H&amp;K HK416</text>
    </string>
	<string id="st_wpn_hk416_descr">
		<text>The HK416 is a rifle designed and manufactured by Heckler&amp;Koch to improve the M4. It is available as a complete firearm, or as an upper receiver that fits on any AR-15 type lower receiver. The US ArmyвЂ™s Delta Force collaborated with the German arms makers to develop the new rifle. Testing the H&amp;K 416 in 2004 revealed that the piston operating system significantly reduces malfunctions while increasing the life of parts. Originally conceived as an improvement based on the Colt M4 carbine family issued to the U.S. military, with the notable inclusion of an HK-proprietary short-stroke gas piston system derived from the Heckler&amp;Koch G36.</text>
	</string>
<!-- L85A2 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_l85">
		<text>L85A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_descr">
		<text>The development of the SA80 system, which included two weapons - the SA80 IW assault rifle and SA80 LSW light machine gun, began in the late 1960s when the British Army decided to develop a new rifle, to replace the aging 7.62x51mm L1 SLR British made FN FAL. The standard individual weapon for the British armed forces, the L85 (in its original A1 version) had numerous performance issues. The improved L85A2 is extremely reliable over a range of climates for various operational scenarios. The current L85A2 rifles are recognized as reliable and accurate, especially when using standard issue SUSAT telescope sights.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Z-M LR-300ML -->
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300">
		<text>LR-300-ML</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_descr">
		<text>Based on the AR-15, the LR 300 is an excellent weapon system suitable for military use in close quarters battle. Its folding skeletal stock makes it ideal for aggressive and rapid building entries requiring a compact yet powerful selective fire weapon. With excellent ergonomics and lightweight, this weapon is highly accurate but it is sensitive to dirt and is not ideal for difficult field conditions.</text>
	</string>
<!-- M590A1 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m590a1">
		<text>Mossberg M590A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m590a1_descr">
		<text>Mossberg 590 was developed by O.F.Mossberg &amp; sons company during 1970s in US as a modification of the Mossberg model 500 shotgun for adoption by the US Military. Modifications included strenghtening of the receiver, installation of the vented heatshield around the barrel, a bayonet lug and extended magazine and an aluminum trigger guard instead of plastic one. Standard finish is Parkerizing, and the gun is provided with replacement pistol grip, which allows easy converion to 'Cruiser' modification. Since 1987, this was the standard shotgun of US Armed forces; officially replaced in US Army with Benelli M1014 semi automatic shotgun, Mossberg 590 shotguns are still used by US Navy and US Marine Corp.</text>
	</string>
<!-- M4 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m4">
		<text>M4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m4_descr">
		<text>The M4 Carbine descends from a family of firearms tracing its lineage back to earlier carbine versions of the M16, all based on the original AR-15 made by ArmaLite. It is a shorter and lighter version of the M16 assault rifle, sharing 80% of its parts. The M4 fires 5.56x45mm NATO ammunition and are gas operated, air cooled, magazine fed, selective fire firearms with a 4 position telescoping stock. As with many carbines, the M4 is handy and more convenient to carry than a full length rifle. It has been adopted by United States Special Operations Command (USSOCOM) and is the preferred weapon of the U.S. Army Special Forces and Navy SEALs.</text>
	</string>
<!-- M4A1 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_m4a1">
        <text>Colt M4A1</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_m4a1_descr">
        <text>The M4A1 is used by almost all U.S special operation units including, but not limited to, Marine Force Recon, Army Rangers, Army Special Forces, Navy SEALs, United States Air Force Pararescue and Air Force Combat Control Teams. The M4A1 is especially favored by counter-terrorist and special forces units for close quarters combat and urban warfare because of the carbine's compact firepower.</text>
    </string>
<!-- M16 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m16">
		<text>M16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m16_descr">
        <text>The M16 is the U.S. military designation for a family of rifles derived from the ArmaLite AR-15 and further developed by Colt starting in 1960s. The M16 rifle family including the M16/A1/A2/A3/A4 has been the primary infantry rifle of the United States military since the 1960s. With its variants, it has been in use by 15 NATO countries, and is the most produced firearm in its caliber. The M16 is a lightweight, 5.56x45mm caliber, air cooled, gas operated, magazine fed assault rifle, with a rotating bolt, actuated by direct impingement gas operation. The rifle is made of steel, aluminum, and composite plastics.</text>
	</string>
<!-- M16A1 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a1">
		<text>M16A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a1_descr">
		<text>An M16 with a forward assist feature requested by the Army. All of the early versions were chambered to fire the M193/M196 cartridge in the semi automatic and the automatic firing modes. This occurred in the early 1960s, with the Army issuing it in late 1964. M16A1s were first issued to Special Forces troops in spring of 1964.</text>
	</string>
<!-- M16A2 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a2">
		<text>M16A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a2_descr">
		<text>The M16A2 rifle entered service in the 1980s, chambered to fire the standard NATO round, the Belgian designed M855/M856 cartridge. The M16A2 is a select fire rifle, incorporating design elements requested by the Marine Corps: an adjustable, windage rear sight, longer stock, heavier barrel, case deflector for left-hand shooters and cylindrical hand guards. The M16A2 is manufactured by Colt and the Fabrique Nationale de Herstal arms company, with the variant rifles made elsewhere in the world.</text>
	</string>
<!-- M16A3 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a3">
		<text>M16A3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a3_descr">
		<text>By 1996, a newest version of the M16 appeared, the M16A3. This rifle differs from the M16A2 by having a removable carry handle, with the upper receiver being fitted with a Picatinny rail. The M16A3 also replaced the three-round burst mode with an automatic mode. The key advantage of both the M16A3 rifle is the ability to quickly mount a wide variety of optical, red dot or night vision/IR sights with MIL-STD 1913 Picatinny-type compatible mounts.</text>
	</string>
<!-- M16A4 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a4">
		<text>M16A4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m16a4_descr">
		<text>Developed along with the M16A3, the M16A4 differ from the M16A2 by having a removable carry handle, with the upper receiver being fitted with a Picatinny rail. Otherwise the M16A4 is similar to the M16A2. The key advantage of the A4 rifle is the ability to quickly mount a wide variety of optical, red dot or night vision/IR sights with MIL-STD 1913 Picatinny-type compatible mounts.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_m16a4_camo">
        <text>M16A4 (Camo)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_m16a4_camo_descr">
        <text>A variant of the M16A4 rifle with a desert camo pattern and Leupold Mark 4 sight.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K MP5 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_mp5">
        <text>H&amp;K MP5A3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_mp5_descr">
        <text>This submachine gun has gained popularity around the world thanks to its reliability, ease of use and accuracy. Over the last few decades the MP5 was in service with special armed forces and police units worldwide. Not surprisingly, having flooded the global black markets, it eventually made its way to the Zone.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K UMP -->
    <string id="st_wpn_ump45">
        <text>H&amp;K UMP-45</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_ump45_descr">
        <text>The H&amp;K UMP (Universal Machine Pistol) is a series of submachine guns from Heckler&amp;Koch as a lighter and cheaper alternative to the H&amp;K MP5. The UMP's action is blow-back firing from a closed bolt as opposed to the MP5's delayed roller blow-back action.</text>
    </string>
<!-- H&amp;K MP5SD -->
    <string id="st_wpn_mp5sd">
        <text>H&amp;K MP5SD</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_mp5sd_descr">
        <text>In 1974 H&amp;K initiated design work on a sound-suppressed variant of the MP5, designated the MP5SD. Which features an integral but detachable aluminium sound suppressor and a lightweight bolt. The suppressor itself is divided into two stages; the initial segment surrounding the ported barrel serves as an expansion chamber for the propellant gases, reducing gas pressure to slow down the acceleration of the projectile. The second, decompression stage occupies the remaining length of the suppressor tube and contains a stamped metal helix separator with several compartments which increase the gas volume and decrease its temperature, deflecting the gases as they exit the muzzle, so muffling the exit report. The bullet leaves the muzzle at subsonic velocity, so it does not generate a sonic shock wave in flight.</text>
    </string>
<!-- ПП-2000 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_pp2000">
		<text>PP-2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pp2000_descr">
		<text>The PP-2000 is the latest development of the Instrument Design Bureau (KBP) from Tula, Russia. First displayed to the public in 2004, the patent for its layout has been filed in 2001 and was issued in 2003. The niche for the PP-2000 is a personal defense weapon for non-infantry military personnel, as well as close combat weapon for special forces and special law enforcement teams. As such, it is a compact weapon with few parts for reliability, simplified maintenance and low cost. Best suited for close combat.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ПБ -->
	<string id="st_wpn_pb">
		<text>PB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pb_descr">
		<text>The PB (Pistolet Besshumnyj or Silent Pistol), also known in the Soviet army as 6P9, has been developed in 1967 for Spetsnaz units of the Soviet Army, as well as for KGB operatives. The pistol is based on a modified Makarov PM pistol and features an unique integral two part suppressor. Issued into service in 1967, the PB (GRAU index 6P9) is a Soviet silenced pistol based on the Makarov PM. It was intended for use by the KGB and army reconnaissance groups. The front part of the suppressor is detachable, so that the pistol can be broken down into two parts for convenient carry. The PB's integral suppressor also reduces the bullet velocity to below subsonic levels.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ПМ -->
	<string id="st_wpn_pm">
		<text>PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_descr">
		<text>This Soviet legacy is the most common pistol in the Zone and is one of the best compact self-defense handguns available. It is small, highly reliable, easy to use and maintain in working order. It also suffers from several drawbacks, including short range, low firing accuracy and poor stopping power, while also losing out to modern pistols in its class in terms of weight and magazine size. In 1951, the Pistol Makarova was selected because of its simplicity, easy manufacturing, accuracy, and reasonable stopping power.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ПММ -->
	<string id="st_wpn_pmm">
		<text>PMM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pmm_descr">
		<text>The most widely known variant, the Makarov PMM was a redesign of the original gun. In 1990 a group of engineers reworked the original Makarov, primarily by increasing the load for the cartridge. The result is 25% more gas pressure increasing in muzzle velocity. The PMM magazine holds 12 rounds, compared to the PM's 8 rounds.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Protecta -->
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta">
        <text>Armsel Protecta</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_descr">
		<text>The uniquely designed Armsel Protecta is a rotating cylinder fed 12-gauge shotgun developed for riot control and combat. Antiquated now by the Russian Saiga-12 and the American AA-12, the Protecta was a revolutionary weapon created by the Apartheid government in the 1980s. This smoothbore combat revolver-type shotgun was intended to provide extreme firepower for militarized units. The weapon benefits from a large magazine and a high effective rate of fire, but its bulkiness and considerable weight, combined with a long reload time, are the price to be paid for these advantages. Rare in the Zone and used primarily to clear confined spaces of mutants.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Remington 870 -->
    <string id="st_wpn_remington870">
        <text>Remington 870</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_remington870_descr">
        <text>The Remington Model 870 is a pump-action shotgun manufactured by Remington Arms Company, LLC. It is widely used by the public for sport shooting, hunting, and self-defense. It is also commonly used by law enforcement and military organizations worldwide.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_rg6">
		<text>RG-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rg6_descr">
		<text>This revolver-type grenade launcher uses six rifled front-loading barrels, identical to underbarrel launcher attachments. The drum is also front-loading. Widely used for rapid suppression of enemy firing positions and, when in the open, attacking defended fixed targets or fighting particularly tough monsters.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ПКМ -->
	<string id="st_wpn_pkm">
		<text>PKM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pkm_descr">
		<text>This belt-fed machine gun is a portable modification with a complex two-stage feeding system. Despite its weight and low precision, this LMG has found admirers in the Zone. Used primarily to fight off outnumbering enemy forces during faction conflicts and clear out mutant lairs.</text>
	</string>
<!-- РПГ-7 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_rpg7">
		<text>RPG-7V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rpg7_descr">
		<text>This grenade launcher from the 1960s made its way into the Zone from army depots. The weapon is a smoothbore single-shot recoilless launch system with an open-rear tube. Although its huge size and weight make it an unlikely choice for stalkers, given its huge destructive power and ease of use, it does have its uses.</text>
	</string>
<!-- SIG-P220 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220">
		<text>Glock 17</text>
	</string>
<!-- SIG-P226 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_sig226">
		<text>SIG-Sauer P226</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_descr">
		<text>Designed for professionals, the Glock 17, in 9x19, is the most widely used law enforcement pistol worldwide. Because of its unsurpassed reliability, above-average magazine capacity of 17 rounds in the standard magazine, and its low weight, it is trusted by law enforcement officers around the globe, also it's very popular among the Stalkers in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
<!-- SIG SG-550 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550">
		<text>SIG SG-550</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_descr">
		<text>Renowned for its high production quality and good performance, the SG 550 is often referred to as the finest 5.56 mm rifle ever made. It has a side-folding skeletonized buttstock and a lightweight aluminum bipod that folds into grooves in the lower handguard.</text>
	</string>
<!-- SIG "Стрелок" -->
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok">
		<text>Strelok's SIG SG-550</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok_descr">
		<text>A Swiss-made SGI-5k assault rifle. Although it is hardly new, it is clear that the previous owner took good care of it: the weapon has been taken apart and put back together, with every component fine-tuned for optimum performance, increasing stopping power. The letter "S" has been carved into the stock, along with 16 small notches.</text>
	</string>
<!-- SIG SG-551 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_sig551">
		<text>SIG SG-551</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550-551_descr">
		<text>A relatively new assault rifle that has quickly found admirers around the world, despite lacking a "trendy" design. Weapons of this series are one of the best in their class, renowned for their reliability, accuracy and ease of use.  Despite being relatively difficult to obtain in the Zone, this assault rifle is often ordered by experienced stalkers at considerable expense.</text>
	</string>
<!-- SIG SG-552 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_sig552">
		<text>SG 552 "Commando"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig552_descr">
		<text>The SG 552 Commando is designed for urban combat, making it the most compact member of SIG's renowned SG 550 family. This SG 552 Commando comes equipped with an EOTech holographic sight, which enhances its CQC capabilities.</text>
	</string>
<!-- FN SCAR-L -->
	<string id="st_wpn_scar_light">
		<text>FN SCAR-L</text>
	</string>
<!-- FN SCAR-H -->
	<string id="st_wpn_scar_heavy">
		<text>FN SCAR-H</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_scar_descr">
        <text>The SCAR-H is a 7.62x51 NATO battle rifle made by FN Herstal for the United States Special Operations Command. As of early 2015, the FN SCAR is now in service in over 20 countries around the world. It was selected in 2004 out of the Special Operations Forces (SOF) Combat Assault Rifle Program and officially designated as operationally effective, operationally suitable and sustainable as a result of a 5-week Field User Assessment conducted by operational SOCOM forces in late 2008. These SCAR-H began fielding in April 2009. As of early 2015, the FN SCAR is now in service in over 20 countries around the world.</text>
    </string>
<!-- SPAS-12 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12">
		<text>SPAS-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_descr">
		<text>This special purpose smoothbore automatic shotgun was designed in the second half of the 20th century and comes with pump-action and self-cocking firing modes. Used as an all-purpose weapon by the police and assault troops. Notable for its reliability and tactical flexibility. Despite its large weight, complex mechanism and considerable cost it is in demand in the Zone due to its effectiveness against mutants.</text>
	</string>
<!-- SR-25 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_sr25">
		<text>SR-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sr25_descr">
		<text>The SR-25, Stoner Rifle, model 25 was developed by Reed Knight, owner of Knights Armament Co. and Eugene Stoner. The SR-25 is an AR-15 rifle scaled up to shoot 7.62x51mm NATO or .308 ammunition. 60% of parts in the rifle is interchangeable with AR-15 components. This rifle sold well among civilian shooters who needed an accurate semi automatic rifle in 7.62x51mm NATO or .308 caliber for hunting or target shooting. This rifle also found a favor in US Military. All rifles built on the SR-25 platform share the same basic action, the AR-15/M16 system. Because of AR-15 style recoil buffer, which extends rearwards from the receiver, SR-25 cannot be fitted with a folding stock instead it is fitted with telescoping stock.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_sv98">
		<text>SV-98</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sv98_descr">
		<text>The SV-98 is a Russian bolt action sniper rifle designed by Vladimir Stronskiy. In 2003 special operations troops were armed with the 7.62 mm 6S11 sniper system comprising the SV-98 sniper rifle and 7N14 sniper enhanced penetration round. The rifle has been used in combat since operations in Chechnya.</text>
	</string>
<!-- СВД -->
	<string id="st_wpn_svd">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_descr">
		<text>An army sniper rifle that has been on the market for more than fifty years and has earned its reputation for exceptional reliability and ease of use. The SVD is normally used by the army to improve the effective range of its units, but stalkers respect this weapon for its armor-piercing properties, which allow it to penetrate mutant hide and army body armor.</text>
	</string>
<!-- СВУ -->
	<string id="st_wpn_svu">
		<text>SVU</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_descr">
		<text>A modernized version of the SVD sniper rifle in a compact bullpup design made on the order of rapid response forces. It allows faster precision fire and is considerably lighter, while its single shot firing accuracy at short and medium range is similar to that of its predecessor. These qualities have earned it the admiration of countless stalkers.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_toz194">
		<text>TOZ-194</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz194_descr">
		<text>The TOZ-194 is a 12 Gauge, pump-action shotgun manufactured by the Tula Arms Plant. Designed during the last years of the Soviet Union, the manufacture of this firearm has started after its collapse, and since then it has gained a certain popularity within civilian shooters in Russia itself and in Europe, and is reported to be in use with some Russian Security forces.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ТОЗ-34 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34">
		<text>TOZ-34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_descr">
		<text>This extremely common over-and-under hunting shotgun can offer better protection against mutants than a pistol, thanks to its accuracy and stopping power. Used mostly by rookies on the outskirts of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ТОЗ-66 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_toz66">
		<text>TOZ-66 sawn-off</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz66_descr">
		<text>A common hunting shotgun with the barrel sawn off and the stock removed, making it lighter and more compact than a full shotgun. One of the most popular weapons among bandits due to its combination of ease of concealment and extreme effectiveness in close combat.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_toz66_full">
		<text>TOZ-66</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz66_full_descr">
		<text>Produced between 1968 and 1974, the TOZ-66 is a "side by side" double-barrel shotgun intended for hunting.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Неизвестное оружие -->
    <string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel">
        <text>Unidentified weapon</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel_descr">
        <text>An unknown weapon, the firing mechanism of which has not been established. The weapon appears faulty - squeezing the trigger doesn't do anything.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_vssk">
		<text>VSSK "Exhaust"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vssk_descr">
		<text>The VKS is a Russian bullpup, straight-pull bolt-action sniper rifle chambered for the 12.7x55 mm subsonic round. The weapon is also known by the name VSSK and the additional name Vykhlop. It was developed in 2002 for special forces units of FSB.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_vsk94">
		<text>VSK 94</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vsk94_descr">
		<text>The VSK-94 is a 9 mm suppressed sniper rifle developed by the Russia KBP Instrument Design Bureau as a low-cost alternative to the VSS rifle. The rifle is based on the 9A-91 assault rifle. The VSK-94 was designed to accurately engage unarmored point targets at ranges up to 400 m.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_vepr12">
        <text>Vepr-12</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_vepr12_descr">
        <text>The Vepr-12 is a multipurpose semi-automatic shotgun, created by Molot-Oruzhie Ltd. It is patterned after the original Kalashnikov rifle, and built on the heavy RPK light machine gun receiver. Like the Kalashnikov rifle, it is a rotating bolt, gas-operated gun that feeds from an 10 round magazine.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_svt40">
        <text>SVT-40</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_svt40_descr">
        <text>The SVT-40 is a surplus semi-automatic rifle chambered in the 7.62x54R round. It saw widespread use in the Red Army and Wehrmacht during WWII. Technicians are not interested in upgrading surplus weapons.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_pkp">
		<text>PKP "Pecheneg"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pkp_descr">
		<text>The PKP "Pecheneg" is a Russian light machine gun chambered for the 7.62x54mmR round. It is a modernized PKM machine gun. The Pecheneg is said to be more accurate than all its predecessors due to a heavier, non-removable, forced air cooling barrel with radial cooling ribs and a handle which eliminates the haze effect from hot gases and keeps the barrel cooler, making the weapon more reliable.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_m249">
        <text>M249</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_m249_descr">
        <text>The M249 is a belt fed 5.56x45 machine gun. It is the American adaptation of the Belgian FN Minimi. The M249 has seen action in every major conflict involving the United States since the U.S. invasion of Panama in 1989. Soldiers are generally satisfied with the weapon's performance, though there have been reports of clogging with dirt and sand.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m79">
		<text>M79</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m79_descr">
		<text>The M79 grenade launcher is a single shot, shoulder-fired, break-action grenade launcher that fires a 40x46mm grenade, which uses what the US Army calls the High-Low Propulsion System to keep recoil low. First appeared during the Vietnam War.</text>
	</string>
<!-- H&amp;K USP -->
	<string id="st_wpn_usp">
		<text>H&amp;K USP</text>
	</string>
<!-- H&amp;K USP Match -->
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_match">
		<text>UDP Compact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_descr">
		<text>Impeccable reliability and durability combined with excellent accuracy are the main noteworthy features of this weapon. Its minor drawbacks include its considerable size, relatively high center of gravity and massive bolt, which make it difficult to conceal but do not outweigh the weapon's positive features. The weapon is especially popular with the Zone's veterans.</text>
	</string>
<!-- АС «Вал» -->
	<string id="st_wpn_val">
		<text>SA Avalanche</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_val_descr">
		<text>A modified version of the silent Vintar BC sniper rifle, this assault rifle was designed as a special forces weapon. The rifle's primary purpose is effective fire against enemies employing modern personal protection equipment without disclosing the shooter's location. Thanks to its integrated silencer and 9x39 calibre round with a heavy subsonic bullet, the weapon's noise and muzzle flash have been reduced to a minimum.</text>
	</string>
<!-- СР-3 «Вихрь» -->
	<string id="st_wpn_vihr">
		<text>SR-3M "Vikhr"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vihr_descr">
		<text>The SR-3 "Vikhr" ("Whirlwind") compact assault rifle was developed in CNIITochMash and manufactured by Tula Arms Plant. Initially known as "MA" (Malogabaritnyj Avtomat - small size assault rifle), it was based on the suppressed 9x39mm AS-Val assault rifle, and intended for concealed carry by special VIP protection teams and State Security operatives, SR3M Vikhr is result of combining the qualities of SR-3, AS VAL and VSS Vintorez. SR-3M also has a larger capacity of 30 rounds, which also provides more reliable feeding during automatic fire.</text>
	</string>
<!-- ВСС «Винторез» -->
    <string id="st_wpn_vintorez">
        <text>VSS 'Vintorez'</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_vintorez_descr">
        <text>A special military sniper rifle purpose-built for silent, flashless sniping during special operations where early detection of the shooter may be critical. The Vintar BC provides high armor-piercing capability and stopping power, as well as being equipped with an integrated sniper and optical scope. Highly rated by many stalkers despite its small magazine.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Walther P99 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_walther">
		<text>Walther P99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_walther_descr">
		<text>An excellent Western pistol known for its reliability, high capacity magazine and good accuracy, as well as being among the most ergonomic handguns in its class. One of the most widely used pistols in the Zone, both among professionals and rookies who can afford it.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_usas12">
		<text>USAS-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_usas12_descr">
		<text>USAS-12 - автоматическое ружьё, разработанное Джоном Тревором в конце 1980-х годов на основе идей другого американского конструктора Максвелла Атчиссона, создавшего Atchisson Assault Shotgun.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_rpd">
		<text>RPD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rpd_descr">
		<text>The RPD (Degtyaryov hand-held machine gun) is a light machine gun developed in the Soviet Union by Vasily Degtyaryov for the intermediate 7.62x39mm M43 cartridge.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300">
		<text>Chaser 13</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_descr">
		<text>A Western smoothbore shotgun that is extremely popular around the world thanks to its amazing reliability and faster reloading speed. Particularly valued for its functionality by the Zone's hunters. All of its parts are coated with an anti-corrosion compound.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_mine_name">
    		<text>Butterfly mine</text>
  	</string>
  	<string id="st_wpn_mine_descr">
		<text>The PFM-1 is an anti-personnel mine which became infamous for causing large numbers of civilian casualties. Often referred to as a butterfly mine due to its unusual shape.</text>
  	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addons_box">
        <text>Multi-Tool</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_addons_box_descr">
        <text>Compact multi tool with numerous hex bits and punch tools used to unmount optical sights.</text>
    </string>
<!-- Walther WA 2000 -->
	<string id="st_wpn_wa2000">
		<text>Walther WA 2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wa2000_descr">
        <text>The WA2000 is a bullpup sniper rifle, designed by the Walther company. Only 176 were built due to the high cost of the rifle making it currently rare and valuable.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_knife_survival">
        <text>Survival knife</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_knife_survival_descr">
        <text>A short non-folding survival knife. Easy to conceal due to its small size. A rubber gripped handle allows for improved handling.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_knife_spetsnaz">
        <text>NR-2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_knife_spetsnaz_descr">
        <text>A military survival knife manufactured for the Spetsnaz during the Soviet era. The NR-2 is a variant of the NRS-2 but lacking the single-shot shooting mechanism.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_knife_tanto">
        <text>Tanto knife</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_knife_tanto_descr">
        <text>A modern tanto-style combat knife. Literally meaning "short knife", a tanto is a Japanese blade from the feudal era. The origin of this knife is unknown as it is unbranded.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_knife_colt">
        <text>Colt 62316</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_knife_colt_descr">
        <text>The Colt 62316 is an American military M7 bayonet intended to be fixed to the end of a rifle or shotgun. Introduced in 1964, it first saw service in the Vietnam War.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_knife_extrema">
        <text>Extrema Ratio MK 2.1</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_knife_extrema_descr">
        <text>The Extrema Ratio MK 2.1 is a steel knife based on the historic USMC Ka-Bar. Developed and produced for use by the Italian military and special forces.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_knife_hunting">
        <text>Hunting knife</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_knife_hunting_descr">
        <text>A modern hunting knife with a camouflage pattern. Roughly half a dozen barbs run along the top of the blade, making its removal from flesh very difficult.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_1p29_detector">
		<text>Прицел УСП-1 «Тюльпан» (Регулируемая кратность)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_1p29_detector_descr">
		<text>Унифицированный стрелковый прицел УСП-1 предназначен для ведения прицельной стрельбы из автомата АК-74Н, АК-74М, АН-94 и пулеметов РПК-74Н и ПКМН в светлое время суток и ночью по светящимся и подсвечиваемым целям. 1П29 - индекс прицела УСП-1 Главного артиллерийского управления МО СССР. Создан в рамках ОКР «Тюльпан», откуда и получил своё название. (одна установка)</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_pso-1m2-01_detector">
		<text>Прицел ПСО-1М2-01 (Регулируемая кратность)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_pso-1m2-01_detector_descr">
		<text>ПСО-1М2-01 - прицел для прицельной стрельбы из специальной снайперской винтовки (нарезной) ВСС калибра 9 мм и специального автомата АС калибра 9 мм. Прицельные шкалы рассчитаны для стрельбы от 100 м до 400 метров (шаг 50 метров). Для стрельбы в сумерках в прицелах предусмотрена подсветка сетки. В качестве источника питания в настоящее время взамен аккумулятора 2РЦ63 применяется стандартная батарея типа АА. (одна установка)</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_acog_detector">
		<text>Прицел ACOG (Регулируемая кратность)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_acog_detector_descr">
		<text>4-х кратный оптический прицел для винтовок НАТО. (одна установка)</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a1-s">
		<text>M4A1 "Сайрекс"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a1-s_descr">
		<text>М4А1 с интегрированным глушителем и уникальной раскраской под названием "Сайрекс".</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_mn91">
		<text>Mosin-Nagant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mn91_descr">
		<text>A basic version of the Mosin-Nagant with slightly worn interiors. The M1891/30 was produced for standard issue to all Soviet infantry from 1930 to 1945. It was extremely successful in World War II as a sniper rifle when it was equipped with a 4x PE or a 3.5x PU scope.</text>
        </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a4_howl">
		<text>M4A4 "Вой"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m4a4_howl_descr">
		<text>Уникальная винтовка М4 с вручную нанесённым изображением скалящегося волка.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_trg22">
		<text>TRG-22</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_trg22_descr">
        <text>The TRG-22 is a bolt-action sniper rifle chambered for 7.62x51. Built by the Finnish firearm manufacturer SAKO at Riihimaki.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble">
		<text>SVD "Lynx"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble_descr">
		<text>A hand-assembled version of the SVDm-2 sniper rifle with improved mechanisms for increased flatness. Little difference in appearance, but provides an ideal combination of accuracy and stopping power.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_stg58">
        <text>StG 58</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_stg58_descr">
        <text>The Sturmgewehr 58 (StG 58) is an FAL battle rifle manufactured under license by Steyr-Daimler-Puch and was formerly the standard rifle of the Austrian Army. It is essentially a user customized version of the FAL and is still in use in the Austrian forces. It was selected in a 1958 competition, beating the Spanish CETME and American AR-10.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m60">
		<text>M60</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m60_descr">
        <text>The M60 is a belt fed 7.62x51 machine gun first introduced in 1957. It served with every branch of the U.S. military. Eventually finding its way on to the black market and into The Zone.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble">
		<text>OTs-14-1A "Storm"</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble_descr">
        <text>An experimental version of an assault rifle and grenade launcher system, a Russian modification of the standard Thunder S14, this weapon was specially designed for units operating in the Zone. Notable for its increased magazine capacity.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_groza1">
        <text>OTs-14 Groza</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_groza1_descr">
        <text>This assault rifle combined with a grenade launcher, which is similar to the AKM series, was specially developed for rapid response units. The main differences are its 7.62x39 caliber ammunition, bullpup layout and extensive configuration options. This weapon is highly valued by military stalkers due to its ability to kill enemies wearing body armor behind improvised cover at a distance during urban combat, as well as its excellent stopping power.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_m14">
		<text>M14 EBR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_m14_descr">
        <text>The M14 EBR is an American designated marksman rifle chambered for the 7.62x51mm NATO round It is a variant of the M14 battle rifle and was originally built for use with units of the United States Special Operations Command, such as the Navy SEALs, Delta Force, and task specific ODA units. It found its way into The Zone through a member of Black's mercenary squad.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_hk417">
        <text>H&amp;K HK417</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_hk417_descr">
        <text>The HK417 is a battle rifle designed and manufactured in Germany by Heckler&amp;Koch. The HK417 is intended for use as a designated marksman rifle and in other roles where the greater penetrative power and range of the 7.62x51mm NATO round are required. It has been adopted for service by a number of armed forces, special forces, police organizations and the mercenaries.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble">
		<text>VSS "Tide"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble_descr">
		<text>A special variant of the famous VSS sniper rifle. This model has been extensively customized. Its internal mechanism has been replaced with a better one, which results in increased muzzle velocity and accuracy. It has an effective range of up to 600 meters.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_sks">
        <text>SKS</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_sks_descr">
        <text>The SKS is a surplus semi-automatic carbine chambered in the 7.62x39 round. The Zone's gunsmiths have modified this rifle to use a detachable 20 round magazine. Increasing it's fire power and reducing reload time.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ak12_762">
		<text>AK-12 M43</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ak12_556">
		<text>AK-12 M44</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_m134">
        <text>M134 Minigun</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_m134_descr">
        <text>The M134 Minigun is a 7.62x51 mm NATO, six-barrel machine gun with a rate of fire of 2000 rounds per minute. It features Gatling-style rotating barrels with an external power source, normally an electric motor. The "Mini" in the name is in comparison to designs that use a similar firing mechanism but larger shells, such as General Electric's earlier 20mm M61 Vulcan, and "gun" for a caliber size smaller than that of a cannon, typically 20 mm and higher.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ace21">
		<text>Galil ACE-21</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ace21_descr">
		<text>The Galil ACE family is designed and produced by the Israeli arms company IWI Ltd. The basis of the ACE Galil rifles is the Galil assault rifle, which in its turn is based on Kalashnikov's AK rifle. The Galil ACE focuses on ergonomics, ease of use and integration with additional attachments, as well as flexibility in combat - the Galil ACE family includes the three most common types of ammunition in the world (5.56x45 NATO, 7.62x39 M43 and NATO 7.62x51), with multiple barrel lengths for each type.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_vityaz">
		<text>ПП-19-01 "Витязь"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vityaz_descr">
		<text>Вариант ПП-19 с 30-зарядным секторным магазином под патрон 9x19 мм, разработан в 2004 году. Применяется для вооружения патрульно-постовых служб, ГИБДД, внутриведомственной охраны, и подразделений МВД РФ.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_mp412">
        <text>MP-412 REX</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_mp412_descr">
        <text>The MP412 REX is a Russian double-action .357 magnum revolver with a break-action chamber and an automatic ejector. It was designed for export (REX, Revolver for EXport), but never put into full production due to lack of a market. The revolver was designed by IZHMECH, the state-owned Russian Izhevsk Mechanical Plant, which also designed and produced the Makarov PM semi-automatic pistol. </text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_fnc">
		<text>FN FNC</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fnc_descr">
		<text>FN FNC (Fabrique Nationale Carabine - карабин фирмы FN) - бельгийский автомат, созданный оружейной фирмой Fabrique Nationale de Herstal для замены устаревшей FN FAL, после неудачи с первым вариантом оружия под малоимпульсный патрон калибра 5,56 мм НАТО FN CAL.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_mtar21">
		<text>MTAR-21</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mtar21_descr">
		<text>MTAR-21 - карабин с компоновкой "булл-пап" является ультра-компактной версией стандартной винтовки израильской армии TAR-21. Обладает великолепной эргономикой и легок в обращении, благодаря длине всего в 590 мм. Предназначен для использования в условиях городского боя, когда стандартная винтовка слишком громоздка.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41">
		<text>PPSh-41</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ppsh41_descr">
		<text>A major infantry weapon of the Soviet armed forces during World War II, the PPSh-41 was a durable, low-maintenance weapon made of cheap, easily-obtained components. They utilize 7.62x25mm cartridge.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_nimble">
		<text>ТОЗ-34 "Охотник"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_nimble_descr">
		<text>Уникальный ТОЗ-34 Гонты с прицелом Leupold Mark для стрельбы на дальних расстояниях.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_trg42">
		<text>TRG-42</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_trg42_descr">
		<text>Снайперская винтовка с продольно-скользящим затвором под патрон .338 Lapua, разработанная финской компанией SAKO в г. Рийхимяки. Винтовки серии Sako TRG отличаются высокой точностью стрельбы и живучестью, и широко используются силовыми структурами европейских стран.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
    <string id="st_wpn_l115a3">
        <text>L115A3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_l115a3_descr">
        <text>The L115A3 is a bolt action sniper rifle chambered in .338 Lapua. In 1982 the British Army adopted the Accuracy International PM into service as the L115A3 and outfitted the rifle with Schmidt &amp; Bender 6x42 telescopic sights. In this configuration the rifle is capable of first shot hits with a cold, warm or fouled barrel.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->    
	<string id="st_wpn_mp7">
        <text>H&amp;K MP7</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_wpn_mp7_descr">
        <text>The MP7 is a German Personal Defense Weapon (PDW) manufactured by Heckler&amp;Koch and chambered for the H&amp;K 4.6x30mm cartridge. It was designed to meet NATO requirements published in 1989, that call for a PDW class firearm with greater ability to defeat body armor.</text>
    </string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_addon_scope_pu">
		<text>PU scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_pu_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue telescopic sight of the Red Army in World War II and years after it, designed to fit infantry and precision rifles such as Mosin-Nagant or SVT-40. It features a fixed 3.5x zoom making it a good choice for long-distance combat. Like all Soviet designs, it is durable and effective, remaining in production and use to this day.</text>
	</string>
<!-- insert name -->
	<string id="st_wpn_aek973">
		<text>АЕК-973</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_aek973_descr">
		<text>The AEK-973 is a 7.62x39mm version of AEK-971 developed at the Kovrov Mechanical Plant under the direction of Stanislav Ivanovich Koksharov based on SA-006 system. Based on previous AK rifles in internal design and layout, the AEK-973 is also equipped with a recoil-balancing mechanism, resulting in more controllable automatic fire. Small batches of this rifle were manufactured for the Russian MVD.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
