<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="trenchcoat_brown_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit leather trench coat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trenchcoat_brown_outfit_description">
		<text>A regular trench coat that hides a stalker bodysuit underneath it. Said bodysuit comes with reinforced body armour made by bandit craftsmen providing good protection against anomalies. The suit cannot be modified with an artefact container, but may be upgraded with a combat support system instead.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_outfit_name">
		<text>Soldier uniform</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_outfit_description">
		<text>A poor protective outfit contracted by government bureaucrats outsourcing to the lowest bidder. It slightly increases bullet, shrapnel and bite protection. For the soldiers serving in the Zone, it is as good as walking naked amidst rifle bullets and anomalies.</text>
	</string>

 	<string id="barmerc_outfit_name">
		<text>Bar guard uniform</text>
  	</string>
  	<string id="barmerc_outfit_description">
		<text>The uniform used by guards in and around the 100 Rads bar. Its design is based on the outfit used by mercenaries around the Zone. Due to a special treatment of the fabric, the armour has much strengthened stability to offset the physical movement of its plates. Its protective properties are slightly better then those of the PSZ-7 military bulletproof suits.</text>
  	</string>

	<string id="cs_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Clear Sky scientific suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cs_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This suit, produced by one of Kiev's Defence Research Institutes, is a great alternative to home-made stalker suits. While its built-in body armour can only stop light rounds, the anomaly and radiation protection system is second to none. Fully upgradeable and boasting a built-in artefact container, this bodysuit is the equipment of choice for many experienced stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="nbc_outfit_name">
		<text>NBC suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nbc_outfit_description">
		<text>The NBC suit is an advanced version of the standard Sunrise suit. It is composed of a camouflaged CBRN suit with a Class III Kevlar vest. Comes standard with a GP-5 gas mask using a hose leading to a modern filter. Comes with a built-in artefact container.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="cs_nbc_outfit_name">
		<text>Clear Sky NBC suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cs_nbc_outfit_description">
		<text>The Clear Sky NBC suit is an advanced version of the standard CS-1 Body Armour. It is composed of a camouflaged CBRN suit with a Class III Kevlar vest. Comes standard with a GP-5 gas mask using a hose leading to a modern filter. Comes with a built-in artefact container.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="monolith_nbc_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith NBC suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_nbc_outfit_description">
		<text>The Monolith NBC suit is an advanced version of the standard Monolith suit. It is composed of a camouflaged CBRN suit with a Class III Kevlar vest. Comes standard with a GP-5 gas mask using a hose leading to a modern filter. Comes with a built-in artefact container.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>Radiation suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>The best in personal protection technology. Composed of three elements - a tactical helmet, a heavy armoured vest and reinforced jumpsuit. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be reinforced with composite or titanium plates for increased protection. Comes with a built-in artefact container.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="dolg_radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>Duty radiation suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>The best in personal protection technology. Composed of three elements - a tactical helmet, a heavy armoured vest and reinforced jumpsuit. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be reinforced with composite or titanium plates for increased protection. Does not come with a built-in artefact container.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="svoboda_radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom radiation suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>The best in personal protection technology. Composed of three elements - a tactical helmet, a heavy armoured vest and reinforced jumpsuit. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be reinforced with composite or titanium plates for increased protection. Comes with a built-in artefact container.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="merc_radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>Mercenary radiation suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>The best in personal protection technology. Composed of three elements - a tactical helmet, a heavy armoured vest and reinforced jumpsuit. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be reinforced with composite or titanium plates for increased protection. Comes with two built-in artefact containers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="monolith_radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith radiation suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>The best in personal protection technology. Composed of three elements - a tactical helmet, a heavy armoured vest and reinforced jumpsuit. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be reinforced with composite or titanium plates for increased protection. Comes with two built-in artefact containers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_outfit_name">
		<text>UNISG outfit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="isg_outfit_description">
		<text>This bodysuit is a combination of a bodysuit of twin-layered rubberised cloth with Plexiglas lining and built-in body armour. Created specifically for members of the now defunct United Nations International Scientific Group, this suit is modelled after the popular Sunrise suit. Comes with built-in artefact containers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="isg_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>UNISG SEVA suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="isg_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>A suit once worn by brave UNISG scientists who foraged into Zone's most anomalous areas. It provides good protection from bullet and shrapnel hit, but not enough for large-scale hostilities. Fully upgradeable and boasting two built-in artefact containers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bandit_specops_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit Berill-5M armoured suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_specops_outfit_description">
		<text>An upgraded version of the common bandit body armour. The vest includes PSZ-9a series military body armour and many other upgrades to protect the wearer against anomalies and radiation.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="cs_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Clear Sky exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cs_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>An experimental sample of an exoskeleton painted in Clear Sky colours, their demand is high between veterans of the Clear Sky faction. Comes with a built-in artefact containers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_helm_tactic_2">
		<text>Tactical M12 helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic_2_descr">
		<text>An aluminium/titanium helmet with an armour face mask and a cloth exterior that comes with pockets for additional steel armour pieces providing the maximum head protection possible. The Tactical M12 is normally used as part of a combination that includes PSZ series Spetsnaz body armour. It is quite rare in the Zone thanks to its limited production. It comes with a built-in first generation night vision device as well as electronics slots. </text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_2_descr">
		<text>A regular plastic and rubber gas mask, used for filtering air for radioactive particles and poisonous substances. This older model is still widely used by rookies and veterans of all factions due to its universal functionality and cheap price. Does not provide any physical protection.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_helm_facemask">
		<text>Mask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_facemask_descr">
		<text>A piece of cloth for covering one's mouth. Protects wearer from inhaling dust. You should probably invest in a respirator.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="cs_stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Clear Sky Sunrise suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cs_stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>A Clear Sky branded Sunrise bodysuit. Despite the fact that the body armour is incapable of protecting the wearer from even pistol bullets, the suit enjoys great popularity within Clear Sky members due to its low cost and modification potential. Comes with built-in artefact container.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="scientific_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy SEVA suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>A modified SEVA suit with heavier emphasis on body armour. The anomaly protection features have slightly suffered due to this change of priorities. Fully upgradeable and boasting two built-in artefact containers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="exo_proto_outfit_name">
		<text>Sunrise exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_proto_outfit_description">
		<text>A standard Sunrise bodysuit fitted into a old military grade exoskeleton. Offers the same amount of protection as a standard Sunrise, but with greatly increased carrying capacity. Where the hell did you find this?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_half">
		<text>Respirator</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_respirator_half_descr">
		<text>A regular plastic and rubber respirator, used to protect the wearer from inhaling harmful dusts, fumes, vapours or gases. Widely used by rookies and veterans of all factions due to its universal functionality. Does not provide any physical protection.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_gp5">
		<text>GP-5 gas mask</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_respirator_gp5_descr">
		<text>The GP-5 was designed to protect civilians of the Soviet Union from radioactive fallout during the Cold War and was manufactured from 1962 to 1989. This mask is a helmet-type mask which was made in both white and black rubber. The lenses of these masks are held in place by crimped metal rims, crimped onto the rubber of the mask. The bottom of the mask is made of metal, and in it is the 40mm filter input, and the inhale and exhale valves. The GP-5 is widely used by loners and bandits due to its availability and cheap price.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
