<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>
	
	<string id="isg_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Researchers exoskeleton </text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>Researchers prefer to use heavy materials for the best protection from bullets, which literally turns the bearer of this reservation in the tank. In the composition of the armor consists of rigid metal, plastic and ceramic plates, and flexible elements made of aramid fabric. The disadvantage is the very low protection against anomalies, which even the weakest of them can in a moment destroy this tank.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Researchers ПС7-3M "Battleship"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Early model of the suit of "Researchers" - the body armor of special forces series ПС7-3M, adapted for use in the Zone. The right combination of rigid and flexible elements made it possible to provide the highest possible level of protection while retaining the ease of operation and mobility of the fighter. Able to protect against machine-gun bullets, but very bulky and almost never provides protection from abnormal influences. Installation of containers for artifacts is not provided, but is possible to install various auxiliary systems.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_heavy_proto_name">
		<text>Researchers ПС7-3ms "Battleship"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_heavy_proto_description">
		<text>Early model of the suit of "Researchers" - the body armor of special forces series ПС7-3M, adapted for use in the Zone. The right combination of rigid and flexible elements made it possible to provide the highest possible level of protection while retaining the ease of operation and mobility of the fighter. Able to protect against machine-gun bullets, but very bulky and almost never provides protection from abnormal influences. Installation of containers for artifacts is not provided, but is possible to install various auxiliary systems.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>"Researchers" radiation suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>by far the best example of modern technology. The costume consists of three elements: reinforced jumpsuit, heavy body armor and an integrated tactical helmet. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be further strengthened using composite or titanium plates for improved protection against bullets and shrapnel. Not equipped with containers for artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_outfit_proto_name">
		<text>Researchers proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="isg_outfit_proto_description">
		<text>Created specifically for members of the International Research Group, the jumpsuit is a combination of the two-layer rubberized fabric lined in Plexiglas with built-in body armor and fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. This suit is modeled after the popular Sunrise suit.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="military_novice_name">
		<text>Military outfit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="military_novice_description">
		<text>A poor protective outfit contracted by government bureaucrats outsourcing to the lowest bidder. It slightly increases bullet, shrapnel and bite protection. For soldiers serving in the Zone, it is as good as walking naked amidst rifle bullets and anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="helm_exo_name">
		<text>Exohelm</text>
	</string>

	<string id="helm_exo_descr">
		<text>This helmet resembles that of an ordinary exoskeleton, but differs sightly from its standard counterpart and has differing protective characteristics. Good protection from gunfire and high caliber rounds in combination with anomaly protection make this helmet one of the best in its category.</text>
	</string> 

	<string id="bandit_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit Berill-5M armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Created specifically for members of the Bandits, this item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter modified for use in the Zone. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="csky_outfit_proto_name">
		<text>Clear Sky proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="csky_outfit_proto_description">
		<text>A Clear Sky branded sunrise bodysuit fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. Despite the fact that the body armor is incapable of protecting the wearer from even pistol bullets, the suit enjoys great popularity within Clear Sky members due to its low cost and modification potential.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy military armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>by far the best example of modern technology. The costume consists of three elements: reinforced jumpsuit, heavy body armor and an integrated tactical helmet. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be further strengthened using composite or titanium plates for improved protection against bullets and shrapnel. Has a built-in container for artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_commander_proto_name">
		<text>Army bronekostyum "SKAT-9M" (servo)</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_commander_proto_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_heavy_proto_name">
		<text>SKAT-9 proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_heavy_proto_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, an anomalous protection bodysuit, mounted exoskeleton. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_outfit_proto_name">
		<text>Monolith proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_outfit_proto_description">
		<text>Stalker suit from the Monolith faction fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. The producer is unknown. Its protective properties are slightly worse then those of the PSZ-9a military bulletproof vest. Its structure is similar to the suit popular with neutral stalkers which combines a bulletproof vest and a radiation protection suit. It provides good protection from gunfire.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="stalker_outfit_proto_name">
		<text>Sunrise suit proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="stalker_outfit_proto_description">
		<text>This DIY stalker bodysuit is a combination of twin-layered rubberized cloth with Plexiglas lining and built-in body armor. Despite the fact that the body armor is often strained by anything beyond even pistol bullets, the suit enjoys great popularity due to its low cost and modification potential.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="csky_heavy_proto_name">
		<text>Clear Sky Berill-5M proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="csky_heavy_proto_description">
		<text>Created specifically for members of Clear Sky, this item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mono_heavy_proto_name">
		<text>Monolith Berill-5M proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mono_heavy_proto_description">
		<text> An armored suit from the Monolith faction fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. The producer is unknown. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="merc_heavy_proto_name">
		<text>Mercenary Berill-5M proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="merc_heavy_proto_description">
		<text>Created specifically for members of the Mercenaries, this item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ecolog_guard_proto_name">
		<text>Ecologist guard proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ecolog_guard_proto_description">
		<text>Created specifically for members of the Ecologists, this bodysuit is a combination of a bodysuit of twin-layered rubberized cloth with Plexiglas lining and built-in body armor fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. This suit is modeled after the popular Sunrise suit.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_heavy_proto_name">
		<text>Bandits Berill-5M proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_heavy_proto_description">
		<text>Customized by the Bandits, this item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_heavy_name">
		<text>Bandit Berill-5M armored suit</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bandit_heavy_description">
		<text>Customized by the Bandits, this item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter modified for use in the Zone. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="freedom_heavy_proto_name">
		<text>Freedom Berill-5M proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="freedom_heavy_proto_description">
		<text>Customized by Freedom craftsmen, this item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="freedom_outfit_proto_name">
		<text>Freedom proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="freedom_outfit_proto_description">
		<text>A lightweight stalker bodysuit, made by Freedom craftsmen and fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. The suit's fabric is treated with Horizon, a special solution developed by the faction by trial and error, to increase resistance to anomalies.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_heavy_proto_name">
		<text>Duty PSZ-9d proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_heavy_proto_description">
		<text>This early model of the Duty bodysuit is the Spetsnaz PSZ-9 body armor fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. The suit is capable of stopping a rifle bullet, however, this level of protection comes at the cost of its weight, bulkiness and virtually non-existent anomaly protection. Mounted exoskeleton provides extra carry weight.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_heavy_proto_h_name">
		<text>Duty PSZ-9d proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="dolg_heavy_proto_h_description">
		<text>This early model of the Duty bodysuit is the Spetsnaz PSZ-9 body armor fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. The suit is capable of stopping a rifle bullet, however, this level of protection comes at the cost of its weight, bulkiness and virtually non-existent anomaly protection. Mounted exoskeleton provides extra carry weight.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_outfit_proto_name">
		<text>Duty PS5-M proto-exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_outfit_proto_description">
		<text>This modern version of the Duty bodysuit has been fitted with parts from an exoskeleton for additional protection. Unlike the PSZ series, the rest of the suit provides reasonable protection against anomalies while also being capable of stopping a pistol bullet.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="stalker_reinforced_outfit_name">
		<text>Broncobeat "Sunrise"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="stalker_reinforced_outfit_description">
		<text>cardan Developed a version of the heavy armored jumpsuit Stalker, ICCPR-3A Sunrise. The basis components of various costumes and exoskeleton prototypes available in the Area. Basic steel armor based ekzoskeleta, army body armor and berilium coating, built-in aluminum-a titanium helmet with bruneleschi and jumpsuit abnormal protection. Despite the manual Assembly provides excellent protection against bullets and fragments while convenient, hardly limits the mobility of the carrier. With 2 containers for artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_scientific_name">
		<text>Army bronekostyum insulating</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_scientific_description">
		<text>Army bronekostyum insulating GAGARIN is created for conducting assault operations in the extreme conditions of the Zone. Has an external insulating coating and a breathing system of the closed cycle, where the key element is modification of the gas mask GP-17. Thanks to such solution perfectly protects against abnormal impacts. The basis of armor protection is the modification of vests series Fort Redoubt T7, which provides excellent protection against bullets and shell fragments, while not reducing the mobility of the owner. Despite the excellent protective properties from the point of view of the stalkers has the following disadvantages: small portable weight and lack of built-in containers for artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="freedom_skat_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom SKAT-9 "Bulat" armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="freedom_skat_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="killer_skat_outfit_name">
		<text>Mercenary SKAT-9 "Bulat" armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="killer_skat_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_skat_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith SKAT-9 "Bulat" armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_skat_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="csky_skat_outfit_name">
		<text>Clear Sky SKAT-9 "Bulat" armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="csky_skat_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_skat_outfit_name">
		<text>Duty SKAT-9 "Bulat" armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_skat_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="duty_skat_outfit_name">
		<text>Duty SKAT-9 "Bulat" armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="duty_skat_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_skat_1_name">
		<text>SKAT-9 "Bulat" armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_skat_1_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_skat_2_name">
		<text>SKAT-9 "Bulat" armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_skat_2_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Mainly designed for Spetsnaz units for the purposes of high risk operations. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="shram_outfit_name">
		<text>Cloak "Scar"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="shram_outfit_description">
		<text>This cloak belonged to the Mercenary Scar. Cloak has a very high protective characteristics, 5 built-in containers for artifacts and PNV 2nd generation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_seva_dolg_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton "SEVA-M Debt"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_seva_dolg_outfit_description">
		<text>Modification of the exoskeleton by adding the closed system of breathing, which has improved the performance of radiation protection and psi radiation, but made his head more vulnerable. The modification made on the basis of the Exoskeleton of the "Debt" that allowed heavy units to go in debt for a long period of raids with high radiation and anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_seva_merc_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton "SEVA-M Mercenaries"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_seva_merc_outfit_description">
		<text>Модификация экзоскелета путем добавления замкнутой системы дыхания, что позволило повысить показатели защиты от радиации и пси излучения, но сделало голову более уязвимой. Модификация сделана на базе Экзоскелета «Наёмников», что позволило тяжёлым отрядам наёмников выходить в длительные рейды с высокой аномальной и радиационной активностью.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="exo_seva_free_outfit_name">
		<text>Экзоскелет «СЕВА-М Свободы»</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="exo_seva_free_outfit_description">
		<text>Модификация экзоскелета путем добавления замкнутой системы дыхания, что позволило повысить показатели защиты от радиации и пси излучения, но сделало голову более уязвимой. Модификация сделана на базе Экзоскелета «Свободы», что позволило тяжёлым отрядам анархистов выходить в длительные рейды с высокой аномальной и радиационной активностью.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="exo_seva_mono_outfit_name">
		<text>Экзоскелет «СЕВА-М Монолита»</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="exo_seva_mono_outfit_description">
		<text>Модификация экзоскелета путем добавления замкнутой системы дыхания, что позволило повысить показатели защиты от радиации и пси излучения, но сделало голову более уязвимой. Модификация сделана на базе Экзоскелета «Монолита», что позволило тяжёлым отрядам фанатиков выходить в длительные рейды с высокой аномальной и радиационной активностью.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="exo_seva_voen_outfit_name">
		<text>Экзоскелет «СЕВА-М Военных»</text>
	</string>
	

	<string id="exo_seva_voen_outfit_description">
		<text>Modification of the exoskeleton by adding the closed system of breathing, which has improved the performance of radiation protection and psi radiation, but made his head more vulnerable. The modification made on the basis of Exoskeleton Military, which allowed heavy units painstalker to go in long raids with high radiation and anomalous activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_commander_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton "SEVA-M War"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="army_commander_description">
		<text>Army bronekostyum Heavy broascasting established for carrying out assault operations in the areas of activity anomalies. In stock: heavy army bronekostyum series PSZ-12P, built-in compensation suit, helmet Sphere-12M. Provides excellent protection against bullet and shrapnel hits, it does not reduce the mobility of the soldier. In the presence of a balanced system protection from abnormal influences.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="helm_battle_dolg_name">
		<text>a Helmet "Sphere M12 Debt-M"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="helm_battle_dolg_descr">
		<text>Modification of the eponymous helmet. Installed heavy-duty filters. Army PNV 2nd generation. Is possible to install an infrared scanner and improvement plan.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="cs_radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy bronekostyum "CP-4A"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="cs_radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>by far the best example of modern technology. The costume consists of three elements: reinforced jumpsuit, heavy body armor and an integrated tactical helmet. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be further strengthened using composite or titanium plates for improved protection against bullets and shrapnel. Has a built-in container for artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_radiation_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy bronekostyum "Godfather-M"</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_radiation_outfit_description">
		<text>of Course the best example of patsanskogo outfit. The chest is decorated with the symbols of the dangerous boys. In this suit, all the pigeons will know who's coming. The costume consists of three elements: reinforced jumpsuit, heavy body armor and an integrated tactical helmet. The vest consists of several thick layers of Kevlar and can be further strengthened using composite or titanium plates for improved protection against bullets and shrapnel. Has a built-in container for artifacts.</text>
	</string>


	
</string_table>